{"test_questions": [[{"question": "With which network type will OSPF establish router adjacencies but not perform the DR/BDR election process?", "opta": "Point-to-point", "optb": "Backbone area 0", "optc": "Broadcast multi-access", "optd": "Non-broadcast multi-access", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No DR is assigned on any type of point-to-point link. No DR/BDR is assigned on the NBMA point-to-multipoint due to the hub/spoke topology. DR and BDR are elected on broadcast and non-broadcast multi-access networks. Frame Relay is a non-broadcast multi-access (NBMA) network by default."}, {"question": "Which of the following describe the process identifier that is used to run OSPF on a router?\n  It is locally significant.\n  It is globally significant.\n  It is needed to identify a unique instance of an OSPF database.\n  It is an optional parameter required only if multiple OSPF processes are running on the router.", "opta": "1, 2 and 4", "optb": "1 and 3", "optc": "3 and 5", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The Process ID for OSPF on a router is only locally significant and you can use the same number on each router, or each router can have a different number-it just doesn't matter. The numbers you can use are from 1 to 65,535. Don't get this confused with area numbers, which can be from 0 to 4.2 billion."}, {"question": "A network administrator needs to configure a router with a distance-vector protocol that allows classless routing. Which of the following satisfies those requirements?", "opta": "IGRP", "optb": "OSPF", "optc": "RIPv1", "optd": "EIGRP", "opte": "IS-IS", "ans": "D", "explanation": "In this question, we're calling EIGRP just plain old distance vector. EIGRP is an \"advanced\" distance-vector routing protocol, sometimes called a hybrid routing protocol because it uses the characteristics of both distance-vector and link-state routing protocols."}, {"question": "What is the administrative distance of OSPF?", "opta": "90", "optb": "100", "optc": "110", "optd": "120", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The administrative distance (AD) is a very important parameter in a routing protocol. The lower the AD, the more trusted the route. If you have IGRP and OSPF running, by default IGRP routes would be placed in the routing table because IGRP has a lower AD of 100. OSPF has an AD of 110. RIPv1 and RIPv2 both have an AD of 120, and EIGRP is the lowest, at 90."}, {"question": "Your company is running IGRP using an AS of 10. You want to configure EIGRP on the network but want to migrate slowly to EIGRP and don't want to configure redistribution. What command would allow you to migrate over time to EIGRP without configuring redistribution?", "opta": "router eigrp 11", "optb": "router eigrp 10", "optc": "router eigrp 10 redistribute igrp", "optd": "router igrp combine eigrp 10", "ans": "B", "explanation": "If you enable EIGRP on a router with the same autonomous system (AS) number, EIGRP will automatically redistribute IGRP into EIGRP. You will see the IGRP injected routes as external (EX) routes with an EIGRP AD of 170. This is a nice feature that lets you migrate slowly to EIGRP with no extra configuration."}, {"question": "Where are EIGRP successor routes stored?", "opta": "In the routing table only", "optb": "In the neighbor table only", "optc": "In the topology table only", "optd": "In the routing table and the topology table", "opte": "In the routing table and the neighbor table", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Successor routes are going to be in the routing table since they are the best path to a remote network. However, the topology table has a link to each and every network, so the best answer is topology table and routing table. Any secondary route to a remote network is considered a feasible successor, and those routes are only found in the topology table and used as backup routes in case of primary route failure."}, {"question": "Which command will display all the EIGRP feasible successor routes known to a router?", "opta": "show ip routes *", "optb": "show ip eigrp summary", "optc": "show ip eigrp topology", "optd": "show ip eigrp adjacencies", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Any secondary route to a remote network is considered a feasible successor, and those routes are only found in the topology table and used as backup routes in case of primary route failure. You can see the topology table with the show ip eigrp topology command."}, {"question": "Which is true regarding EIGRP successor routes?\n  A successor route is used by EIGRP to forward traffic to a destination.\n  Successor routes are saved in the topology table to be used if the primary route fails.\n  Successor routes are flagged as \"active\" in the routing table.\n  A successor route may be backed up by a feasible successor route.\n  Successor routes are stored in the neighbor table following the discovery process.", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "2 and 3", "optc": "1 and 4", "optd": "3, 4 and 5", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Successor routes are the routes picked from the topology table as the best route to a remote network, so these are the routes that IP uses in the routing table to forward traffic to a remote destination. The topology table contains any route that is not as good as the successor route and is considered a feasible successor, or backup route. Remember that all routes are in the topology table, even successor routes."}, {"question": "Which EIGRP information is held in RAM and maintained through the use of Hello and update packets?\n  Neighbor table\n  STP table\n  Topology table\n  DUAL table", "opta": "2 only", "optb": "4 only", "optc": "1 and 3", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "EIGRP holds three tables in RAM: neighbor, topology, and routing. The neighbor and topology tables are built and maintained with the use of Hello packets."}, {"question": "Which of the following are true regarding OSPF areas?\n  You must have separate loopback interfaces configured in each area.\n  The numbers you can assign an area go up to 65,535.\n  The backbone area is also called area 0.\n  If your design is hierarchical, then you don't need multiple areas.\n  All areas must connect to area 0.", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "1 and 2 only", "optc": "3 and 4 only", "optd": "3, 4 and 5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Loopback interfaces are created on a router, and the highest IP address on a loopback (logical) interface becomes the RID of the router but has nothing to do with areas and is optional, so (1) is wrong. The numbers you can create an area with are from 0 to 4,294,967,295 option (2) is wrong. The backbone area is called area 0, so option (3) is correct. All areas must connect to area 0, so option (5) is correct. If you have only one area, it must be called area 0. This leaves option (4), which must be correct; it doesn't make much sense, but it is the best answer."}, {"question": "What are reasons for creating OSPF in a hierarchical design?\n  To decrease routing overhead\n  To speed up convergence\n  To confine network instability to single areas of the network\n  To make configuring OSPF easier", "opta": "1, 2 and 3", "optb": "3 only", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "2, 3 nd 4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "OSPF is created in a hierarchical design, not a flat design like RIP. This decreases routing overhead, speeds up convergence, and confines network instability to a single area of the network."}, {"question": "Which two of the following commands will place network 10.2.3.0/24 into area 0?\n router eigrp 10\n router ospf 10\n network 10.0.0.0\n network 10.2.3.0 0.0.0.255 area0\n network 10.2.3.0 0.0.0.255 area 0", "opta": "1 and 4", "optb": "2, 4, and 5", "optc": "2 and 5", "optd": "3 and 4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "To enable OSPF, you must first start OSPF using a Process ID. The number is irrelevant; just choose a number from 1 to 65,535 and you're good to go. After you start the OSPF process, you must configure any network that you want advertised via OSPF using wildcards and the area command. Statement (4) is wrong because there must be a space after the parameter area and before you list the area number."}, {"question": "If routers in a single area are configured with the same priority value, what value does a router use for the OSPF Router ID in the absence of a loopback interface?", "opta": "The lowest IP address of any physical interface", "optb": "The highest IP address of any physical interface", "optc": "The lowest IP address of any logical interface", "optd": "The highest IP address of any logical interface", "ans": "B", "explanation": "At the moment of OSPF process startup, the highest IP address on any active interface will be the Router ID (RID) of the router. If you have a loopback interface configured (logical interface), then that will override the interface IP address and become the RID of the router automatically."}, {"question": "Which of the following protocols support VLSM, summarization, and discontiguous networking? \n  RIPv1\n  IGRP\n  EIGRP\n  OSPF\n  BGP\n  RIPv2", "opta": "1 and 4", "optb": "2 and 5", "optc": "3, 4 and 6", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "RIPv1 and IGRP are true distance-vector routing protocols and can't do much, really-except build and maintain routing tables and use a lot of bandwidth! RIPv2, EIGRP, and OSPF build and maintain routing tables, but they also provide classless routing, which allows for VLSM, summarization, and discontiguous networking."}, {"question": "You get a call from a network administrator who tells you that he typed the following into his router:\nRouter(config)#router ospf 1\nRouter(config-router)#network 10.0.0.0 255.0.0.0 area 0\nHe tells you he still can't see any routes in the routing table. What configuration error did the administrator make?", "opta": "The wildcard mask is incorrect.", "optb": "The OSPF area is wrong.", "optc": "The OSPF Process ID is incorrect.", "optd": "The AS configuration is wrong.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The administrator typed in the wrong wildcard mask configuration. The wildcard should have been 0.0.0.255."}, {"question": "Which of the following network types have a designated router and a backup designated router assigned?\n  Broadcast\n  Point-to-point\n  NBMA\n  NBMA point-to-point", "opta": "1, 2 and 3", "optb": "1 and 3", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No DR is assigned on any type of point-to-point link. No DR/BDR is assigned on the NBMA point-to-multipoint due to the hub/spoke topology. DR and BDR are elected on broadcast and non-broadcast multi-access networks. Frame Relay is a non-Broadcast Multi-Access (NBMA) network by default."}, {"question": "Which type of OSPF network will elect a backup designated router?\n  Broadcast multi-access\n  Non-broadcast multi-access\n  Point-to-point\n  Broadcast multipoint", "opta": "1 and 2", "optb": "3 and 4", "optc": "3 only", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "DR and BDR are elected on broadcast and non-broadcast multi-access networks. Frame Relay is a non-broadcast multi-access (NBMA) network by default. No DR is assigned on any type of point-to-point link. No DR/BDR is assigned on the NBMA point-to-multipoint due to the hub/spoke topology."}, {"question": "You need the IP address of the devices with which the router has established an adjacency. Also, the retransmit interval and the queue counts for the adjacent routers need to be checked. What command will display the required information?", "opta": "show ip eigrp adjacency", "optb": "show ip eigrp topology", "optc": "show ip eigrp interfaces", "optd": "show ip eigrp neighbors", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The show ip eigrp neighbors command allows you to check the IP addresses as well as the retransmit interval and queue counts for the neighbors that have established an adjacency."}, {"question": "Which layer 1 devices can be used to enlarge the area covered by a single LAN segment?\n  Switch\n  NIC\n  Hub\n  Repeater\n  RJ45 transceiver", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "1 and 3", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "5 only", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Not that you really want to enlarge a single collision domain, but a hub (multiport repeater) will provide this for you."}, {"question": "Routers operate at layer _____. LAN switches operate at layer _____. Ethernet hubs operate at layer _____. Word processing operates at layer _____.", "opta": "3, 3, 1, 7", "optb": "3, 2, 1, none", "optc": "3, 2, 1, 7", "optd": "3, 3, 2, none", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Routers operate at layer 3. LAN switches operate at layer 2. Ethernet hubs operate at layer 1. Word processing applications communicate to the Application layer interface, but do not operate at layer 7, so the answer would be none."}, {"question": "Which of the following describe router functions?", "opta": "Packet switching", "optb": "Packet filtering", "optc": "Internetwork communication", "optd": "Path selection", "opte": "All of the above", "ans": "E", "explanation": "Routers provide packet switching, packet filtering, internetwork communication, and path selection."}, {"question": "Why does the data communication industry use the layered OSI reference model?\n  It divides the network communication process into smaller and simpler components, thus aiding component development, design, and troubleshooting.\n  It enables equipment from different vendors to use the same electronic components, thus saving research and development funds.\n  It supports the evolution of multiple competing standards and thus provides business opportunities for equipment manufacturers.\n  It encourages industry standardization by defining what functions occur at each layer of the model.", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "1 and 4", "optc": "2 and 3", "optd": "3 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The main advantage of a layered model is that it can allow application developers to \nchange aspects of a program in just one layer of the layer model's specifications. Advantages \nof using the OSI layered model include, but are not limited to, the following: It divides the \nnetwork communication process into smaller and simpler components, thus aiding compo-\nnent development, design, and troubleshooting; it allows multiple-vendor development \nthrough standardization of network components; it encourages industry standardization by \ndefining what functions occur at each layer of the model; it allows various types of network \nhardware and software to communicate; and it prevents changes in one layer from affecting \nother layers, so it does not hamper development."}, {"question": "A receiving host has failed to receive all of the segments that it should acknowledge. What can the host do to improve the reliability of this communication session?", "opta": "Send a different source port number.", "optb": "Restart the virtual circuit.", "optc": "Decrease the sequence number.", "optd": "Decrease the window size.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "A receiving host can control the transmitter by using flow control (TCP uses Windowing by default). By decreasing the window size, the receiving host can slow down the transmitting host so the receiving host does not overflow its buffers."}, {"question": "What are the decimal and hexadecimal equivalents for the binary number 10110111?", "opta": "69/0x2102", "optb": "183/B7", "optc": "173/A6", "optd": "83/0xC5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "You must be able to take a binary number and convert it into both decimal and hexadecimal. \nTo convert to decimal, just add up the 1s using their values. The values that are turned on with \nthe binary number of 10110111 are 128 + 32 + 16 + 4 + 2 + 1 = 183. To get the hexadecimal \nequivalent, you need to break the eight binary digits into nibbles (4 bits), 1011 and 0111. By add-\ning up these values, you get 11 and 7. In hexadecimal, 11 is B, so the answer is 0xB7."}, {"question": "What is the purpose of flow control?", "opta": "To ensure that data is retransmitted if an acknowledgment is not received.", "optb": "To reassemble segments in the correct order at the destination device.", "optc": "To provide a means for the receiver to govern the amount of data sent by the sender.", "optd": "To regulate the size of each segment.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Flow control allows the receiving device to control the transmitter so the receiving device's buffer does not overflow."}, {"question": "Which three statements are true about the operation of a full-duplex Ethernet network?\n  There are no collisions in full-duplex mode.\n  A dedicated switch port is required for each full-duplex node.\n  Ethernet hub ports are preconfigured for full-duplex mode.\n  In a full-duplex environment, the host network card must check for the availability of the network media before transmitting.\n  The host network card and the switch port must be capable of operating in full-duplex mode.", "opta": "1, 2, and 5", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "2, 3 and 4", "optd": "5 only", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Full-duplex means you are using both wire pairs simultaneously to send and receive data. You must have a dedicated switch port for each node, which means you will not have collisions. Both the host network card and the switch port must be capable and set to work in full-duplex mode."}, {"question": "Which of the following are types of flow control?\n  Buffering\n  Cut-through\n  Windowing\n  Congestion avoidance", "opta": "1 and 2", "optb": "1, 3 and 4", "optc": "2 only", "optd": "3 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The common types of flow control are buffering, windowing, and congestion avoidance."}, {"question": "What are two purposes for segmentation with a bridge?\n  To add more broadcast domains.\n  To create more collision domains.\n  To add more bandwidth for users.\n  To allow more broadcasts for users.", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "2 and 3", "optc": "2 and 4", "optd": "4 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Bridges break up collision domains, which allow more bandwidth for users."}, {"question": "How does a host on an Ethernet LAN know when to transmit after a collision has occurred?\n  In a CSMA/CD collision domain, multiple stations can successfully transmit data simultaneously.\n  In a CSMA/CD collision domain, stations must wait until the media is not in use before transmitting.\n  You can improve the CSMA/CD network by adding more hubs.\n  After a collision, the station that detected the collision has first priority to resend the lost data.\n  After a collision, all stations run a random backoff algorithm. When the backoff delay period has expired, all stations have equal priority to transmit data.", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "1,3 and 4", "optd": "2 and 5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Once transmitting stations on an Ethernet segment hear a collision, they send an extended jam signal to ensure that all stations recognize the collision. After the jamming is complete, each sender waits a predetermined amount of time, plus a random time. After both timers expire, they are free to transmit, but they must make sure the media is clear before transmitting and that they all have equal priority."}, {"question": "Which of the following types of connections can use full duplex?\n  Hub to hub\n  Switch to switch\n  Host to host\n  Switch to hub\n  Switch to host", "opta": "1, 2 and 4", "optb": "3 and 4", "optc": "3 and 5", "optd": "2, 3 and 5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Hubs cannot run full-duplex Ethernet. Full duplex must be used on a point-to-point connection between two devices capable of running full duplex. Switches and hosts can run full duplex between each other, but a hub can never run full duplex."}, {"question": "Acknowledgments, sequencing, and flow control are characteristics of which OSI layer?", "opta": "Layer 2", "optb": "Layer 3", "optc": "Layer 4", "optd": "Layer 7", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A reliable Transport layer connection uses acknowledgments to make sure all data is transmitted and received reliably. A reliable connection is defined by a virtual circuit that uses acknowledgments, sequencing, and flow control, which are characteristics of the Transport layer (layer 4)."}, {"question": "Which fields are contained within an IEEE Ethernet frame header?\n  Source and destination MAC address\n  Source and destination network address\n  Source and destination MAC address and source and destination network address\n  FCS field", "opta": "1 and 4", "optb": "2 only", "optc": "2 and 3 only", "optd": "3 only", "ans": "A", "explanation": "An Ethernet frame has source and destination MAC addresses, an Ether-Type field to identify the Network layer protocol, the data, and the FCS field that holds the answer to the CRC."}, {"question": "What type of RJ45 UTP cable do you use to connect a PC's COM port to a router or switch console port?", "opta": "Straight-through", "optb": "Crossover cable", "optc": "Crossover with a CSU/DSU", "optd": "Rolled", "ans": "D", "explanation": "To connect to a router or switch console port, you would use an RJ45 UTP rolled cable."}, {"question": "How to implement a network medium that is not susceptible to EMI. Which type of cabling should you use?", "opta": "Thicknet coax", "optb": "Thinnet coax", "optc": "Category 5 UTP cable", "optd": "Fiber-optic cable", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Fiber-optic cable provides a more secure, long-distance cable that is not susceptible to EMI interference at high speeds."}, {"question": "Segmentation of a data stream happens at which layer of the OSI model?", "opta": "Physical", "optb": "Data Link", "optc": "Network", "optd": "Transport", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The Transport layer receives large data streams from the upper layers and breaks these up into smaller pieces called segments."}, {"question": "When data is encapsulated, which is the correct order?", "opta": "Data, frame, packet, segment, bit", "optb": "Segment, data, packet, frame, bit", "optc": "Data, segment, packet, frame, bit", "optd": "Data, segment, frame, packet, bit", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The encapsulation method is data, segment, packet, frame, bit."}, {"question": "Which of the following are unique characteristics of half-duplex Ethernet when compared to full-duplex Ethernet?\n  Half-duplex Ethernet operates in a shared collision domain.\n  Half-duplex Ethernet operates in a private collision domain.\n  Half-duplex Ethernet has higher effective throughput.\n  Half-duplex Ethernet has lower effective throughput.", "opta": "2 only", "optb": "1,2 and 3", "optc": "1 and 4", "optd": "4 only", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Unlike full duplex, half-duplex Ethernet operates in a shared collision domain, and it has a lower effective throughput than full duplex."}, {"question": "What type of RJ45 UTP cable is used between switches?", "opta": "Straight-through", "optb": "Crossover cable", "optc": "Crossover with a CSU/DSU", "optd": "Crossover with a router in between the two switches", "ans": "B", "explanation": "To connect two switches together, you would use a RJ45 UTP crossover cable."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands sets the secret password to Cisco?", "opta": "enable secret password Cisco", "optb": "enable secret cisco", "optc": "enable secret Cisco", "optd": "enable password Cisco", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The enable secret password is case sensitive, so the second option is wrong. To set the enable secret <password>, use the enable secret <password> command from global configuration mode."}, {"question": "You type the following command into the router and receive the following output:\nRouter#show serial 0/0\n        ^\n% Invalid input detected at '^' marker.\nWhy was this error message displayed?", "opta": "You need to be in privileged mode.", "optb": "You cannot have a space between serial and 0/0.", "optc": "The router does not have a serial0/0 interface.", "optd": "Part of the command is missing.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "You can view the interface statistics from user mode, but the command is show interface serial 0/0."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will display the current IP addressing and the layer 1 and 2 status of an interface?\n show version\n show protocols\n show interfaces\n show controllers\n show ip interface", "opta": "1, 2 and 4", "optb": "2, 3 and 5", "optc": "3 and 4 only", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The commands show protocols, show interfaces, and show ip interface will show you the layer 1 and 2 status and the IP addresses of your router's interfaces."}, {"question": "You type show running-config and get this output:\n[output cut]\nLine console 0\n    Exec-timeout 1 35\n    Password BIXPASSWD\n    Login\n[output cut]\n\nWhat do the two numbers following the exec-timeout command mean?", "opta": "If no command has been typed in 35 seconds, the console connection will be closed.", "optb": "If no router activity has been detected in 1 hour and 35 minutes, the console will be locked out.", "optc": "If no commands have been typed in 1 minute and 35 seconds, the console connection will be closed.", "optd": "If you're connected to the router by a Telnet connection, input must be detected within 1 minute and 35 seconds or the connection will be closed.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The exec-timeout command is set in minutes and seconds."}, {"question": "What layer of the OSI model would you assume the problem is in if you type show interface serial 1 and receive the following message?\n\"Serial1 is down, line protocol is down.\"", "opta": "Physical layer", "optb": "Data Link layer", "optc": "Network layer", "optd": "None. It is a router problem.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "If you see that a serial interface and the protocol are both down, then you have a Physical layer problem. If you see serial1 is up, line protocol is down, then you are not receiving (Data Link) keepalives from the remote end."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands displays the configurable parameters and statistics of all interfaces on a router?", "opta": "show running-config", "optb": "show startup-config", "optc": "show interfaces", "optd": "show versions", "ans": "C", "explanation": "With the show interfaces command, you can view the configurable parameters, get statistics for the interfaces on the router, verify if the interfaces are shut down, and see the IP address of each interface."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will configure all the default VTY ports on a router?", "opta": "Router#line vty 0 4", "optb": "Router(config)#line vty 0 4", "optc": "Router(config-if)#line console 0", "optd": "Router(config)#line vty all", "ans": "B", "explanation": "From global configuration mode, use the line vty 0 4 command to set all five default VTY lines."}, {"question": "You need to find the broadcast address used on a LAN on your router. What command will you type into the router from user mode to find the broadcast address?", "opta": "show running-config", "optb": "show startup-config", "optc": "show interfaces", "optd": "show protocols", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The command show ip protocols will actually show you the broadcast address for each interface - too bad it isn't a possible answer. Your best answer is show interfaces, which will provide the IP address and mask for each interface."}, {"question": "Which command will delete the contents of NVRAM on a router?", "opta": "delete NVRAM", "optb": "delete startup-config", "optc": "erase NVRAM", "optd": "erase start", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The erase startup-config command erases the contents of NVRAM and will put you in setup mode if the router is restarted."}, {"question": "What keystroke will terminate setup mode?", "opta": "Ctrl+Z", "optb": "Ctrl+^", "optc": "Ctrl+C", "optd": "Ctrl+Shift+^", "ans": "C", "explanation": "You can exit setup mode at any time by using the keystroke Ctrl+C."}, {"question": "What command do you type to save the configuration stored in RAM to NVRAM?", "opta": "Router(config)#copy current to starting", "optb": "Router#copy starting to running", "optc": "Router(config)#copy running-config startup-config", "optd": "Router#copy run startup", "ans": "D", "explanation": "To copy the running-config to NVRAM so that it will be used if the router is restarted, use the copy running-config startup-config command (copy run start for short)."}, {"question": "You type Router#sh ru and receive an % ambiguous command error. Why did you receive this message?", "opta": "The command requires additional options or parameters.", "optb": "There is more than one show command that starts with the letters ru.", "optc": "There is no show command that starts with ru.", "optd": "The command is being executed from the wrong router mode.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The % ambiguous command error means that there is more then one possible command that starts with ru. Use a question mark to find the correct command."}, {"question": "If you wanted administrators to see a message when logging into the router, which command would you use?", "opta": "message banner motd", "optb": "banner message motd", "optc": "banner motd", "optd": "message motd", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The typical banner is a message of the day (MOTD) and is set by using the global configuration mode command banner motd."}, {"question": "How many simultaneous Telnet sessions does a Cisco router support by default?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Cisco routers, if they do not have the Enterprise edition of the IOS, will default to 5 simultaneous Telnet sessions."}, {"question": "You set the console password, but when you display the configuration, the password doesn't show up; it looks like this:\n[output cut]\nLine console 0\n    Exec-timeout 1 44\n    Password 7098C0BQR\n    Login\n[output cut]\nWhat cause the password to be stored like this?", "opta": "encrypt password", "optb": "service password-encryption", "optc": "service-password-encryption", "optd": "exec-timeout 1 35", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The command service password-encryption, from global configuration mode, will encrypt the passwords."}, {"question": "Which command will show you whether a DTE or a DCE cable is plugged into serial 0?", "opta": "sh int s0", "optb": "sh int serial 0", "optc": "show controllers serial 0", "optd": "show serial 0 controllers", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The show controllers serial 0 command will show you whether either a DTE or DCE cable is connected to the interface. If it is a DCE connection, you need to add clocking with the clock rate command."}, {"question": "You want to totally reinitialize the router and replace the current running-config with the current startup-config. What command will you use?", "opta": "replace run start", "optb": "copy run start", "optc": "copy start run", "optd": "reload", "ans": "D", "explanation": "To completely replace the running-config with the startup-config, you must reload the router. Note : You may have picked option C, which isn't a bad answer. Remember, though, it doesn't replace the configuration, it appends it."}, {"question": "If you delete the contents of NVRAM and reboot the router, what mode will you be in?", "opta": "Privileged mode", "optb": "Global mode", "optc": "Setup mode", "optd": "NVRAM loaded mode", "ans": "C", "explanation": "If you delete the startup-config and reload the router, the router will automatically enter setup mode. You can also type setup from privileged mode at any time."}, {"question": "What is the problem with an interface if you type show interface serial 0 and receive the following message?\n\"Serial0 is administratively down, line protocol is down.\"", "opta": "The keepalives are different times.", "optb": "The administrator has the interface shut down.", "optc": "The administrator is pinging from the interface.", "optd": "No cable is attached.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "If an interface is shut down, the show interface command will show the interface as administratively shut down. (It is possible that no cable is attached, but you can't tell that from this message.)"}, {"question": "Which of the following is true when describing a multicast address?", "opta": "Packets addressed to a unicast address are delivered to a single interface.", "optb": "Packets are delivered to all interfaces identified by the address. This is also called a one-to-many address.", "optc": "Identifies multiple interfaces and is only delivered to one address. This address can also be called one-to-one-of-many.", "optd": "These addresses are meant for nonrouting purposes, but they are almost globally unique so it is unlikely they will have an address overlap.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Packets addressed to a multicast address are delivered to all interfaces identified by the multicast address, the same as in IPv4. It is also called a one-to-many address. You can always tell a multicast address in IPv6 because multicast addresses always start with FF."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true when describing a unicast address?", "opta": "Packets addressed to a unicast address are delivered to a single interface.", "optb": "These are your typical publicly routable addresses, just like a regular publicly routable address in IPv4.", "optc": "These are like private addresses in IPv4 in that they are not meant to be routed.", "optd": "These addresses are meant for nonrouting purposes, but they are almost globally unique so it is unlikely they will have an address overlap.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Packets addressed to a unicast address are delivered to a single interface. For load balancing, multiple interfaces can use the same address."}, {"question": "To enable OSPFv3, which of the following would you use?", "opta": "Router1(config-if)# ipv6 ospf 10 area 0.0.0.0", "optb": "Router1(config-if)# ipv6 router rip 1", "optc": "Router1(config)# ipv6 router eigrp 10", "optd": "Router1(config-rtr)# no shutdown", "opte": "Router1(config-if)# ipv6 eigrp 10", "ans": "A", "explanation": "To enable OSPFv3, you enable the protocol as with RIPng. The command string is ipv6 ospf <process-id> area <area-id>."}, {"question": "What multicast addresses does RIPng use?", "opta": "FF02::A", "optb": "FF02::9", "optc": "FF02::5", "optd": "FF02::6", "ans": "B", "explanation": "RIPng uses the multicast IPv6 address of FF02::9. If you remember the multicast addresses for IPv4, the numbers at the end of each IPv6 address are the same."}, {"question": "Which statement(s) about IPv6 addresses are true?\n  Leading zeros are required.\n  Two colons (::) are used to represent successive hexadecimal fields of zeros.\n  Two colons (::) are used to separate fields.\n  A single interface will have multiple IPv6 addresses of different types.", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "1, 3 and 4", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "In order to shorten the written length of an IPv6 address, successive fields of zeros may be replaced by double colons. In trying to shorten the address further, leading zeros may also be removed. Just as with IPv4, a single device's interface can have more than one address; with IPv6 there are more types of addresses and the same rule applies. There can be link-local, global unicast, and multicast addresses all assigned to the same interface."}, {"question": "To enable RIPng, which of the following would you use?", "opta": "Router1(config-if)# ipv6 ospf 10 area 0.0.0.0", "optb": "Router1(config-if)# ipv6 router rip 1", "optc": "Router1(config)# ipv6 router eigrp 10", "optd": "Router1(config-rtr)# no shutdown", "opte": "Router1(config-if)# ipv6 eigrp 10", "ans": "B", "explanation": "It's pretty simple to enable RIPng for IPv6. You configure it right on the interface where you want RIP to run with the ipv6 router rip number command."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true when describing a global unicast address?", "opta": "Packets addressed to a unicast address are delivered to a single interface.", "optb": "These are your typical publicly routable addresses, just like a regular publicly routable address in IPv4.", "optc": "These are like private addresses in IPv4 in that they are not meant to be routed.", "optd": "These addresses are meant for nonrouting purposes, but they are almost globally unique so it is unlikely they will have an address overlap.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Unlike unicast addresses, global unicast addresses are meant to be routed."}, {"question": "What two multicast addresses does OSPFv3 use?\n FF02::A  \n FF02::9\n FF02::5\n FF02::6", "opta": "2 only", "optb": "3 only", "optc": "1 and 3", "optd": "3 and 4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Adjacencies and next-hop attributes now use link-local addresses, and OSPFv3 still uses multicast traffic to send its updates and acknowledgments with the addresses FF02::5 for OSPF routers and FF02::6 for OSPF designated routers. These are the replacements for 224.0.0.5 and 224.0.0.6, respectively."}, {"question": "What multicast addresses does EIGRPv6 use?", "opta": "FF02::A", "optb": "FF02::9", "optc": "FF02::5", "optd": "FF02::6", "ans": "A", "explanation": "EIGRPv6's multicast address stayed very near the same. In IPv4 it was 224.0.0.10; now it is FF02::A (A=10 in hexadecimal notation)."}, {"question": "To enable EIGRP, which of the following would you use?\n  Router1(config-if)# ipv6 ospf 10 area 0.0.0.0\n  Router1(config-if)# ipv6 router rip 1\n  Router1(config)# ipv6 router eigrp 10\n  Router1(config-rtr)# no shutdown\n  Router1(config-if)# ipv6 eigrp 10", "opta": "1, 3 and 5", "optb": "3, 4 and 5", "optc": "1 and 3", "optd": "5 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Unlike RIPng and OSPFv3, you need to configure EIGRP both from global configuration mode and from interface mode, and you have to enable the command with the no shutdown command."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true when describing a link-local address?", "opta": "Packets addressed to a unicast address are delivered to a single interface.", "optb": "These are your typical publicly routable addresses, just like a regular publicly routable address in IPv4.", "optc": "These are like private addresses in IPv4 in that they are not meant to be routed.", "optd": "These addresses are meant for nonrouting purposes, but they are almost globally unique so it is unlikely they will have an address overlap.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Link-local addresses are meant for throwing together a temporary LAN for meetings or a small LAN that is not going to be routed but needs to share and access files and services locally."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true when describing a unique local address?", "opta": "Packets addressed to a unicast address are delivered to a single interface.", "optb": "These are your typical publicly routable addresses, just like a regular publicly routable address in IPv4.", "optc": "These are like private addresses in IPv4 in that they are not meant to be routed.", "optd": "These addresses are meant for nonrouting purposes, but they are almost globally unique so it is unlikely they will have an address overlap.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "These addresses are meant for nonrouting purposes like link-local, but they are almost globally unique so it is unlikely they will have an address overlap. Unique local addresses were designed as a replacement for site-local addresses."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true when describing an anycast address?", "opta": "Packets addressed to a unicast address are delivered to a single interface.", "optb": "Packets are delivered to all interfaces identified by the address. This is also called one-to-many addresses.", "optc": "This address identifies multiple interfaces and the anycast packet is only delivered to one address. This address can also be called one-to-one-of-many.", "optd": "These addresses are meant for nonrouting purposes, but they are almost globally unique so it is unlikely they will have an address overlap.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Anycast addresses identify multiple interfaces, which is the same as multicast; however, the big difference is that the anycast packet is only delivered to one address, the first one it finds defined in the terms of routing distance. This address can also be called one-to-one-of-many."}, {"question": "You want to ping the loopback address of your local host(with IPv6). What will you type?", "opta": "ping 127.0.0.1", "optb": "ping 0.0.0.0", "optc": "ping ::1", "optd": "trace 0.0.::1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The loopback address with IPv4 is 127.0.0.1. With IPv6, that address is ::1."}, {"question": "Which statement(s) about IPv4 and IPv6 addresses are true?\n  An IPv6 address is 32 bits long, represented in hexidecimal.\n  An IPv6 address is 128 bits long, represented in decimal.\n  An IPv4 address is 32 bits long, represented in decimal.\n  An IPv6 address is 128 bits long, represented in hexidecimal.", "opta": "1 and 3 only", "optb": "2 only", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "2 and 4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "IPv4 addresses are 32 bits long and are represented in decimal format. IPv6 addresses are 128 bits long and represented in hexadecimal format."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements are true regarding the command ip route 172.16.4.0 255.255.255.0 192.168.4.2?\n  The command is used to establish a static route.\n  The default administrative distance is used.\n  The command is used to configure the default route.\n  The subnet mask for the source address is 255.255.255.0.", "opta": "1 and 2", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Although answer D almost seems right, it is not; the mask is the mask used on the remote \nnetwork, not the source network. Since there is no number at the end of the static route, it is \nusing the default administrative distance of 1."}, {"question": "Which command displays RIP routing updates?", "opta": "show ip route", "optb": "debug ip rip", "optc": "show protocols", "optd": "debug ip route", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The debug ip rip command is used to show the Internet Protocol (IP) Routing Information Protocol (RIP) updates being sent and received on the router."}, {"question": "Which statement is true regarding classless routing protocols?\n  The use of discontiguous networks is not allowed.\n  The use of variable length subnet masks is permitted.\n  RIPv1 is a classless routing protocol.\n  IGRP supports classless routing within the same autonomous system.\n  RIPv2 supports classless routing.", "opta": "1, 3 and 5", "optb": "3 and 4", "optc": "2 and 5", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Classful routing means that all hosts in the internetwork use the same mask. Classless routing means that you can use Variable Length Subnet Masks (VLSMs) and can also support discontiguous networking."}, {"question": "You have the following routing table. Which of the following networks will not be placed in the neighbor routing table?\nR    192.168.30.0/24 [120/1] via 192.168.40.1, 00:00:12, Serial0\nC    192.168.40.0/24 is directly connected, Serial0\n     172.16.0.0/24 is subnetted, 1 subnets\nC    172.16.30.0 is directly connected, Loopback0\nR    192.168.20.0/24 [120/1] via 192.168.40.1, 00:00:12, Serial0\nR    10.0.0.0/8 [120/15] via 192.168.40.1, 00:00:07, Serial0\nC    192.168.50.0/24 is directly connected, Ethernet0", "opta": "172.16.30.0", "optb": "192.168.30.0", "optc": "10.0.0.0", "optd": "All of them will be placed in the neighbor routing table.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The network 10.0.0.0 cannot be placed in the next router's routing table because it already is at 15 hops. One more hop would make the route 16 hops, and that is not valid in RIP networking."}, {"question": "What is split horizon?", "opta": "Information about a route should not be sent back in the direction from which the original update came.", "optb": "It splits the traffic when you have a large bus (horizon) physical network.", "optc": "It holds the regular updates from broadcasting to a downed link.", "optd": "It prevents regular update messages from reinstating a route that has gone down.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "A split horizon will not advertise a route back to the same router it learned the route from."}, {"question": "What command is used to stop RIP routing updates from exiting out an interface but still allow the interface to receive RIP route updates?", "opta": "Router(config-if)# no routing", "optb": "Router(config-if)# passive-interface", "optc": "Router(config-router)# passive-interface s0", "optd": "Router(config-router)# no routing updates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The (config-router)#passive-interface command stops updates from being sent out an interface, but route updates are still received."}, {"question": "Two connected routers are configured with RIP routing. What will be the result when a router receives a routing update that contains a higher-cost path to a network already in its routing table?", "opta": "The updated information will be added to the existing routing table.", "optb": "The update will be ignored and no further action will occur.", "optc": "The updated information will replace the existing routing table entry.", "optd": "The existing routing table entry will be deleted from the routing table and all routers will exchange routing updates to reach convergence.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "When a routing update is received by a router, the router first checks the administrative distance (AD) and always chooses the route with the lowest AD. However, if two routes are received and they both have the same AD, then the router will choose the one route with the lowest metrics, or in RIP's case, hop count."}, {"question": "You type debug ip rip on your router console and see that 172.16.10.0 is being advertised to you with a metric of 16. What does this mean?", "opta": "The route is 16 hops away.", "optb": "The route has a delay of 16 microseconds.", "optc": "The route is inaccessible.", "optd": "The route is queued at 16 messages a second.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "You cannot have 16 hops on a RIP network by default. If you receive a route advertised with a metric of 16, this means it is inaccessible."}, {"question": "The Corporate router receives an IP packet with a source IP address of 192.168.214.20 and a destination address of 192.168.22.3. Looking at the output from the Corporate router, what will the router do with this packet?\nCorp#sh ip route\n[output cut]\nR    192.168.215.0 [120/2] via 192.168.20.2, 00:00:23, Serial0/0\nR    192.168.115.0 [120/1] via 192.168.20.2, 00:00:23, Serial0/0\nR    192.168.30.0 [120/1] via 192.168.20.2, 00:00:23, Serial0/0\nC    192.168.20.0 is directly connected, Serial0/0\nC    192.168.214.0 is directly connected, FastEthernet0/0", "opta": "The packet will be discarded.", "optb": "The packet will be routed out the S0/0 interface.", "optc": "The router will broadcast looking for the destination.", "optd": "The packet will be routed out the Fa0/0 interface.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since the routing table shows no route to the 192.168.22.0 network, the router will discard the packet and send an ICMP destination unreachable message out interface FastEthernet 0/0, which is the source LAN where the packet originated from."}, {"question": "If your routing table has a static, a RIP, and an IGRP route to the same network, which route will be used to route packets by default?", "opta": "Any available route", "optb": "RIP route", "optc": "Static route", "optd": "IGRP route", "opte": "They will all load-balance.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Static routes have an administrative distance of 1 by default. Unless you change this, a static route will always be used over any other found route. IGRP has an administrative distance of 100, and RIP has an administrative distance of 120, by default."}, {"question": "What is route poisoning?", "opta": "It sends back the protocol received from a router as a poison pill, which stops the regular updates.", "optb": "It is information received from a router that can't be sent back to the originating router.", "optc": "It prevents regular update messages from reinstating a route that has just come up.", "optd": "It describes when a router sets the metric for a downed link to infinity.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Another way to avoid problems caused by inconsistent updates and to stop network loops is route poisoning. When a network goes down, the distance-vector routing protocol initiates route poisoning by advertising the network with a metric of 16, or unreachable (sometimes referred to as infinite)."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true regarding RIPv2?", "opta": "It has a lower administrative distance than RIPv1.", "optb": "It converges faster than RIPv1.", "optc": "It has the same timers as RIPv1.", "optd": "It is harder to configure than RIPv1.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "RIPv2 is pretty much just like RIPv1. It has the same administrative distance and timers and is configured just like RIPv1."}, {"question": "A network administrator views the output from the show ip route command. A network that is advertised by both RIP and IGRP appears in the routing table flagged as an IGRP route. Why is the RIP route to this network not used in the routing table?", "opta": "IGRP has a faster update timer.", "optb": "IGRP has a lower administrative distance.", "optc": "RIP has a higher metric value for that route.", "optd": "The IGRP route has fewer hops.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "RIP has an administrative distance (AD) of 120, while IGRP has an administrative distance of 100, so the router will discard any route with a higher AD than 100."}, {"question": "What does RIPv2 use to prevent routing loops?\n  CIDR\n  Split horizon\n  Authentication\n  Classless masking\n  Holddown timers", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "2, 3 and 5", "optc": "2 and 5", "optd": "3 and 4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "RIPv2 uses the same timers and loop-avoidance schemes as RIPv1. Split horizon is used to stop an update from being sent out the same interface it was received on. Holddown timers allow time for a network to become stable in the case of a flapping link."}, {"question": "Which two of the following are true regarding the distance-vector and link-state routing protocols?\n  Link state sends its complete routing table out all active interfaces on periodic time intervals.\n  Distance vector sends its complete routing table out all active interfaces on periodic time intervals.\n  Link state sends updates containing the state of its own links to all routers in the internetwork.\n  Distance vector sends updates containing the state of its own links to all routers in the internetwork.", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "3 only", "optc": "2 and 3 only", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The distance-vector routing protocol sends its complete routing table out all active interfaces at periodic time intervals. Link-state routing protocols send updates containing the state of its own links to all routers in the internetwork."}, {"question": "IGRP uses which of the following as default parameters for finding the best path to a remote network?\n  Hop count\n  MTU\n  Cumulative interface delay\n  STP\n  Path bandwidth value", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "3 and 5", "optc": "2, 3 and 5", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "IGRP uses bandwidth and delay of the line, by default, to determine the best path to a remote network. Delay of the line can sometimes be called the cumulative interface delay."}, {"question": "Network 206.143.5.0 was assigned to the Acme Company to connect to its ISP. The administrator of Acme would like to configure one router with the commands to access the Internet. Which commands could be configured on the Gateway router to allow Internet access to the entire network?\n Gateway(config)# ip route 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 206.143.5.2\n Gateway(config)# router rip\n Gateway(config-router)# network 206.143.5.0\n Gateway(config-router)# network 206.143.5.0 default", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "3 only", "optc": "1, 2 and 4", "optd": "1 and 4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "There are actually three different ways to configure the same default route, but only two are shown in the answer. First, you can set a default route with the 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 mask and then specify the next hop, as in option A. Or you can use 0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 and use the exit interface instead of the next hop. Finally, you can use option D with the ip default-network command."}, {"question": "You have your laptop directly connected into a router's Ethernet port. Which of the following are among the requirements for the copy flash tftp command to be successful?\n  TFTP server software must be running on the router.\n  TFTP server software must be running on your laptop.\n  The Ethernet cable connecting the laptop directly into the router's Ethernet port must be a straight-through cable.\n  The laptop must be on the same subnet as the router's Ethernet interface.\n  The copy flash tftp command must be supplied the IP address of the laptop.", "opta": "1, 3 and 4", "optb": "2, 4 and 5", "optc": "3 and 5 only", "optd": "5 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Before you back up an IOS image to a laptop directly connected to a router's Ethernet port, make sure the TFTP server software is running on your laptop, that the Ethernet cable is a \"crossover,\" and that the laptop is in the same subnet as the router's Ethernet port, and then you can use the copy flash tftp command from your laptop."}, {"question": "What information is displayed by the show hosts command?\n  Temporary DNS entries\n  The names of the routers created using the hostname command\n  The IP addresses of workstations allowed to access the router\n  Permanent name-to-address mappings created using the ip host command\n  The length of time a host has been connected to the router via Telnet", "opta": "1, 2 and 3", "optb": "1 and 4", "optc": "3, 4, and 5", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The show hosts command provides information on temporary DNS entries and permanent name-to-address mappings created using the ip host command."}, {"question": "You are unsuccessful in telnetting into a remote device. What could the problem be?\n  IP addresses are incorrect.\n  Access control list is filtering Telnet.\n  There is a defective serial cable.\n  The VTY password is missing.", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "3 only", "optc": "2 and 4 only", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The best answers, the ones you need to remember, are that either an access control list is filtering the Telnet session or the VTY password is not set on the remote device."}, {"question": "Which three commands can be used to check LAN connectivity problems on a router?\n show interfaces\n show ip route\n tracert\n ping\n dns lookups", "opta": "1 ,2 and 4", "optb": "2 and 5", "optc": "3 and 5", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The tracert command is a Windows command and will not work on a router! A router uses the traceroute command."}, {"question": "If you want to have more than one Telnet session open at the same time, what keystroke combination would you use?", "opta": "Tab+Spacebar", "optb": "Ctrl+X, then 6", "optc": "Ctrl+Shift+X, then 6", "optd": "Ctrl+Shift+6, then X", "ans": "D", "explanation": "To keep open one or more Telnet sessions, use the Ctrl+Shift+6 and then X keystroke combination."}, {"question": "Which command will copy the IOS to a backup host on your network?", "opta": "transfer IOS to 172.16.10.1", "optb": "copy run start", "optc": "copy start tftp", "optd": "copy flash tftp", "ans": "D", "explanation": "To copy the IOS to a backup host, which is stored in flash memory by default, use the copy flash tftp command."}, {"question": "Which command loads a new version of the Cisco IOS into a router?", "opta": "copy flash ftp", "optb": "copy ftp flash", "optc": "copy flash tftp", "optd": "copy tftp flash", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The command copy tftp flash will allow you to copy a new IOS into flash memory on your router."}, {"question": "You are troubleshooting a connectivity problem in your corporate network and want to isolate the problem. You suspect that a router on the route to an unreachable network is at fault. What IOS user exec command should you issue?", "opta": "Router> ping", "optb": "Router> trace", "optc": "Router> show ip route", "optd": "Router> show interface", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The command traceroute (trace for short), which can be issued from user mode or privileged mode, is used to find the path a packet takes through an internetwork and will also show you where the packet stops because of an error on a router."}, {"question": "The configuration register setting of 0x2102 provides what function to a router?", "opta": "Tells the router to boot into ROM monitor mode", "optb": "Provides password recovery", "optc": "Tells the router to look in NVRAM for the boot sequence", "optd": "Boots the IOS from a TFTP server", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The default configuration setting of 0x2102 tells the router to look in NVRAM for the boot sequence."}, {"question": "You telnet to a router and make your necessary changes; now you want to end the Telnet session. What command do you type in?", "opta": "close", "optb": "disable", "optc": "disconnect", "optd": "exit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since the question never mentioned anything about a suspended session, you can assume that the Telnet session is still open, and you would just type exit to close the session."}, {"question": "Which command displays the configuration register setting?", "opta": "show ip route", "optb": "show boot version", "optc": "show version", "optd": "show flash", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The show version command provides you with the current configuration register setting."}, {"question": "What should the configuration register value be after you successfully complete the password recovery procedure and return the router to normal operation?", "opta": "0x2100", "optb": "0x2101", "optc": "0x2102", "optd": "0x2142", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All Cisco routers have a default configuration register setting of 0x2102, which tells the router to load the IOS from flash memory and the configuration from NVRAM."}, {"question": "You telnet into a remote device and type debug ip rip, but no output from the debug command is seen. What could the problem be?", "opta": "You must type the show ip rip command first.", "optb": "IP addressing on the network is incorrect.", "optc": "You must use the terminal monitor command.", "optd": "Debug output is sent only to the console.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "To see console messages through your Telnet session, you must enter the terminal monitor command."}, {"question": "What does the command o/r 0x2142 provide?", "opta": "It is used to restart the router.", "optb": "It is used to bypass the configuration in NVRAM.", "optc": "It is used to enter ROM Monitor mode.", "optd": "It is used to view the lost password.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The default configuration setting is 0x2102, which tells the router to load the IOS from flash and the configuration from NVRAM. 0x2142 tells the router to bypass the configuration in NVRAM so that you can perform password recovery."}, {"question": "You save the configuration on a router with the copy running-config startup-config command and reboot the router. The router, however, comes up with a blank configuration. What can the problem be?", "opta": "You didn't boot the router with the correct command.", "optb": "NVRAM is corrupted.", "optc": "The configuration register setting is incorrect.", "optd": "The newly upgraded IOS is not compatible with the hardware of the router.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "If you save a configuration and reload the router and it comes up either in setup mode or as a blank configuration, chances are you have the configuration register setting incorrect."}, {"question": "The corporate office sends you a new router to connect, but upon connecting the console cable, you see that there is already a configuration on the router. What should be done before a new configuration is entered in the router?", "opta": "RAM should be erased and the router restarted.", "optb": "Flash should be erased and the router restarted.", "optc": "NVRAM should be erased and the router restarted.", "optd": "The new configuration should be entered and saved.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Before you start to configure the router, you should erase the NVRAM with the erase startup-config command and then reload the router using the reload command."}, {"question": "Which command will show you the IOS version running on your router?", "opta": "sh IOS", "optb": "sh flash", "optc": "sh version", "optd": "sh running-config", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The best answer is show version, which shows you the IOS file running currently on your router. The show flash command shows you the contents of flash memory, not which file is running."}, {"question": "You need to gather the IP address of a remote switch that is located in Hawaii. What can you do to find the address?", "opta": "Issue the show ip arp command on the router connected to the switch.", "optb": "Issue the show ip route command on the router connected to the switch.", "optc": "Issue the show cdp neighbor command on the router connected to the switch.", "optd": "Issue the show cdp neighbors detail command on the router connected to the switch.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Although option A is certainly the \"best\" answer, unfortunately option  D will work just fine and your boss would probably prefer you to use the show cdp neighbors detail command."}, {"question": "A network administrator wants to upgrade the IOS of a router without removing the image currently installed. What command will display the amount of memory consumed by the current IOS image and indicate whether there is enough room available to hold both the current and new images?", "opta": "show version", "optb": "show flash", "optc": "show memory", "optd": "show buffers", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The show flash command will provide you with the current IOS name and size and the size of flash memory."}, {"question": "You copy a configuration from a network host to a router's RAM. The configuration looks correct, yet it is not working at all. What could the problem be?", "opta": "You copied the wrong configuration into RAM.", "optb": "You copied the configuration into flash memory instead.", "optc": "The copy did not override the shutdown command in running-config.", "optd": "The IOS became corrupted after the copy command was initiated.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Since the configuration looks correct, you probably didn't screw up the copy job. However, when you perform a copy from a network host to a router, the interfaces are automatically shut down and need to be manually enabled with the no shutdown command."}, {"question": "How long is an IPv6 address?", "opta": "32 bits", "optb": "128 bytes", "optc": "64 bits", "optd": "128 bits", "ans": "D", "explanation": "An IPv6 address is 128 bits long."}, {"question": "What flavor of Network Address Translation can be used to have one IP address allow many users to connect to the global Internet?", "opta": "NAT", "optb": "Static", "optc": "Dynamic", "optd": "PAT", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Port Address Translation (PAT) allows a one-to-many approach to network address translation."}, {"question": "What are the two main types of access control lists (ACLs)?\n  Standard\n  IEEE\n  Extended\n  Specialized", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "1 and 2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Standard and extended access control lists (ACLs) are used to configure security on a router."}, {"question": "What command is used to create a backup configuration?", "opta": "copy running backup", "optb": "copy running-config startup-config", "optc": "config mem", "optd": "wr mem", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The command to back up the configuration on a router is copy running-config startup-config."}, {"question": "You have 10 users plugged into a hub running 10Mbps half-duplex. There is a server connected to the switch running 10Mbps half-duplex as well. How much bandwidth does each \nhost have to the server?", "opta": "100 kbps", "optb": "1 Mbps", "optc": "2 Mbps", "optd": "10 Mbps", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Each device has 10 Mbps\tto the server."}, {"question": "Which WLAN IEEE specification allows up to 54Mbps at 2.4GHz?", "opta": "A", "optb": "B", "optc": "G", "optd": "N", "ans": "C", "explanation": "IEEE 802.11B is 2.4GHz, but with a maximum of only 11Mbps. IEEE 802.11G is in the 2.4GHz range, with a top speed of 54Mbps."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the valid host range for the subnet on which the IP address 192.168.168.188 255.255.255.192 resides?", "opta": "192.168.168.129-190", "optb": "192.168.168.129-191", "optc": "192.168.168.128-190", "optd": "192.168.168.128-192", "ans": "A", "explanation": "256 - 192 = 64. 64 + 64 = 128. 128 + 64 = 192. The subnet is 128, the broadcast address \nis 191, and the valid host range is the numbers in between, or 129-190."}, {"question": "To back up an IOS, what command will you use?", "opta": "backup IOS disk", "optb": "copy ios tftp", "optc": "copy tftp flash", "optd": "copy flash tftp", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The command copy flash tftp will prompt you to back up an existing IOS in flash to a TFTP host."}, {"question": "What protocol does PPP use to identify the Network layer protocol?", "opta": "NCP", "optb": "ISDN", "optc": "HDLC", "optd": "LCP", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Network Control Protocol is used to help identify the Network layer protocol used in the packet."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands will allow you to set your Telnet password on a Cisco router?", "opta": "line telnet 0 4", "optb": "line aux 0 4", "optc": "line vty 0 4", "optd": "line con 0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The command line vty 0 4 places you in a prompt that will allow you to set or change your Telnet password."}, {"question": "Which protocol does DHCP use at the Transport layer?", "opta": "IP", "optb": "TCP", "optc": "UDP", "optd": "ARP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "User Datagram Protocol is a connection network service at the Transport layer, and DHCP uses this connectionless service."}, {"question": "Which command is used to determine if an IP access list is enabled on a particular interface?", "opta": "show access-lists", "optb": "show interface", "optc": "show ip interface", "optd": "show interface access-lists", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The show ip interface command will show you if any outbound or inbound interfaces have an access list set."}, {"question": "Where is a hub specified in the OSI model?", "opta": "Session layer", "optb": "Physical layer", "optc": "Data Link layer", "optd": "Application layer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Hubs regenerate electrical signals, which are specified at the Physical layer."}, {"question": "What does the passive command provide to dynamic routing protocols?", "opta": "Stops an interface from sending or receiving periodic dynamic updates.", "optb": "Stops an interface from sending periodic dynamic updates but not from receiving updates.", "optc": "Stops the router from receiving any dynamic updates.", "optd": "Stops the router from sending any dynamic updates.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The passive command, short for passive-interface, stops regular updates from being sent out an interface. However, the interface can still receive updates."}, {"question": "Which protocol is used to send a destination network unknown message back to originating hosts?", "opta": "TCP", "optb": "ARP", "optc": "ICMP", "optd": "BootP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "ICMP is the protocol at the Network layer that is used to send messages back to an originating router."}, {"question": "How often are BPDUs sent from a layer 2 device?", "opta": "Never", "optb": "Every 2 seconds", "optc": "Every 10 minutes", "optd": "Every 30 seconds", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Every 2 seconds, BPDUs are sent out from all active bridge ports by default."}, {"question": "How many broadcast domains are created when you segment a network with a 12-port switch?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "5", "optd": "12", "ans": "A", "explanation": "By default, switches break up collision domains but are one large broadcast domain."}, {"question": "What does the command routerA(config)#line cons 0 allow you to perform next?", "opta": "Set the Telnet password.", "optb": "Shut down the router.", "optc": "Set your console password.", "optd": "Disable console connections.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The command line console 0 places you at a prompt where you can then set your console user-mode password."}, {"question": "Which router command allows you to view the entire contents of all access lists?", "opta": "show all access-lists", "optb": "show access-lists", "optc": "show ip interface", "optd": "show interface", "ans": "B", "explanation": "To see the contents of all access lists, use the show access-lists command."}, {"question": "Which class of IP address has the most host addresses available by default?", "opta": "A", "optb": "B", "optc": "C", "optd": "A and B", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Class A addressing provides 24 bits for host addressing."}, {"question": "In a network with dozens of switches, how many root bridges would you have?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "5", "optd": "12", "ans": "A", "explanation": "You should have only one root bridge per network."}, {"question": "What PPP protocol provides dynamic addressing, authentication, and multilink?", "opta": "NCP", "optb": "HDLC", "optc": "LCP", "optd": "X.25", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Link Control Protocol in the PPP stack provides dynamic addressing, authentication, and multilink."}, {"question": "What is a stub network?", "opta": "A network with more than one exit point.", "optb": "A network with more than one exit and entry point.", "optc": "A network with only one entry and no exit point.", "optd": "A network that has only one entry and exit point.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Stub networks have only one connection to an internetwork. Only default routes can be set on a stub network or network loops may occur."}, {"question": "If your router is facilitating a CSU/DSU, which of the following commands do you need to use to provide the router with a 64000bps serial link?", "opta": "RouterA(config)#bandwidth 64", "optb": "RouterA(config-if)#bandwidth 64000", "optc": "RouterA(config-if)#clock rate 64", "optd": "RouterA(config-if)#clock rate 64000", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The clock rate command is two words, and the speed of the line is in bps."}, {"question": "Which one of the following is true regarding VLANs?", "opta": "Two VLANs are configured by default on all Cisco switches.", "optb": "VLANs only work if you have a complete Cisco switched internetwork. No off-brand switches are allowed.", "optc": "You should not have more than 10 switches in the same VTP domain.", "optd": "VTP is used to send VLAN information to switches in a configured VTP domain.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Switches do not propagate VLAN information by default; you must configure the VTP domain. VLAN Trunking Protocol (VTP) is used to propagate VLAN information across a trunk link."}, {"question": "What does a VLAN do?", "opta": "Acts as the fastest port to all servers.", "optb": "Provides multiple collision domains on one switch port.", "optc": "Breaks up broadcast domains in a layer 2 switch internetwork.", "optd": "Provides multiple broadcast domains within a single collision domain.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "VLANs break up broadcast domains at layer 2."}, {"question": "What is the main reason the OSI model was created?", "opta": "To create a layered model larger than the DoD model.", "optb": "So application developers can change only one layer's protocols at a time.", "optc": "So different networks could communicate.", "optd": "So Cisco could use the model.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The primary reason the OSI model was created was so that different networks could inter-operate."}, {"question": "How many collision domains are created when you segment a network with a 12-port switch?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "5", "optd": "12", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Layer 2 switching creates individual collision domains."}, {"question": "What command will display the line, protocol, DLCI, and LMI information of an interface?", "opta": "sh pvc", "optb": "show interface", "optc": "show frame-relay pvc", "optd": "show run", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The show interface command shows the line, protocol, DLCI, and LMI information of an interface."}, {"question": "Which protocol does Ping use?", "opta": "TCP", "optb": "ARP", "optc": "ICMP", "optd": "BootP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "ICMP is the protocol at the Network layer that is used to send echo requests and replies."}, {"question": "Which command is used to upgrade an IOS on a Cisco router?", "opta": "copy tftp run", "optb": "copy tftp start", "optc": "config net", "optd": "copy tftp flash", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The copy tftp flash command places a new file in flash memory, which is the default location for the Cisco IOS in Cisco routers."}, {"question": "If you wanted to delete the configuration stored in NVRAM, what would you type?", "opta": "erase startup", "optb": "erase nvram", "optc": "delete nvram", "optd": "erase running", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The command erase startup-config deletes the configuration stored in NVRAM."}, {"question": "What protocols are used to configure trunking on a switch?\n  VLAN Trunking Protocol\n  VLAN\n  802.1Q\n  ISL", "opta": "1 and 2", "optb": "3 and 4", "optc": "1 only", "optd": "2 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "VTP is not right because it has nothing to do with trunking except that it sends VLAN information across a trunk link. 802.1Q and ISL are used to configure trunking on a port."}, {"question": "Which command would you place on interface connected to the Internet?", "opta": "ip nat inside", "optb": "ip nat outside", "optc": "ip outside global", "optd": "ip inside local", "ans": "B", "explanation": "As in access-lists, you must configure your interfaces before NAT will provide any translations. On the inside networks you would use the command ip nat inside. On the outside interface, you will use the command ip nat outside."}, {"question": "Which command will show you all the translations active on your router?", "opta": "show ip nat translations", "optb": "show ip nat statistics", "optc": "debug ip nat", "optd": "clear ip nat translations *", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The command show ip nat translations will show you the translation table containing all the active NAT entries."}, {"question": "Which command would you place on interface on a private network?", "opta": "ip nat inside", "optb": "ip nat outside", "optc": "ip outside global", "optd": "ip inside local", "ans": "A", "explanation": "As in access-lists, you must configure your interfaces before NAT will provide any translations. On the inside networks you would use the command ip nat inside. On the outside interface, you will use the command ip nat outside."}, {"question": "Port Address Translation is also termed what?", "opta": "NAT Fast", "optb": "NAT Static", "optc": "NAT Overload", "optd": "Overloading Static", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Another term for port address translation is NAT Overload because that is the command used to enable port address translation."}, {"question": "When creating a pool of global addresses, which of the following can be used instead of the netmask command?", "opta": "/ (slash notation)", "optb": "prefix-length", "optc": "no mask", "optd": "block-size", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Instead of the netmask command, you can use the prefix-length <length> statement."}, {"question": "Which of the following would be a good starting point for troubleshooting if your router is not translating?", "opta": "Reboot.", "optb": "Call Cisco.", "optc": "Check your interfaces for the correct configuration.", "optd": "Run the debug all command.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "In order for NAT to provide translation services, you must have ip nat inside and ip nat outside configured on your router's interfaces."}, {"question": "Which command will show you the summary of the NAT configuration?", "opta": "show ip nat translations", "optb": "show ip nat statistics", "optc": "debug ip nat", "optd": "clear ip nat translations *", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The show ip nat statistics command displays a summary of the NAT configuration as well as counts of active translation types, hits to an existing mapping, misses (causing an attempt to create a mapping), and expired translations."}, {"question": "Which of the following is considered to be the destination host before translation?", "opta": "Inside local", "optb": "Outside local", "optc": "Inside global", "optd": "Outside global", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The host on the global network before translation is considered to be an outside local host."}, {"question": "Which of the following is considered to be the address after translation?", "opta": "Inside local", "optb": "Outside local", "optc": "Inside global", "optd": "Outside global", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The host on the private network after translation is considered to be an inside global host."}, {"question": "Which are considered the methods of NAT?\n  Static\n  IP NAT pool\n  Dynamic\n  NAT double-translation\n  Overload", "opta": "1 and 6", "optb": "3 only", "optc": "1, 3 and 5", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "You can configure NAT three ways on a Cisco router: static, dynamic, and NAT Overload (PAT)."}, {"question": "Which command will allow you to see real-time translations on your router?", "opta": "show ip nat translations", "optb": "show ip nat statistics", "optc": "debug ip nat", "optd": "clear ip nat translations *", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The command debug ip nat will show you in real time the translations occurring on your router."}, {"question": "Which of the following would be good reasons to run NAT?\n  You need to connect to the Internet and your hosts don't have globally unique IP addresses.\n  You change to a new ISP that requires you to renumber your network.\n  You don't want any hosts connecting to the Internet.\n  You require two intranets with duplicate addresses to merge.", "opta": "1, 2 and 4", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "3 only", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The most popular use of NAT is if you want to connect to the Internet and you don't want hosts to have global (real) IP addresses, but option B and D are correct as well."}, {"question": "Which of the following are advantages of using NAT?\n  Translation introduces switching path delays.\n  Conserves legally registered addresses.\n  Causes loss of end-to-end IP traceability.\n  Increases flexibility when connecting to the Internet.\n  Certain applications will not function with NAT enabled.\n  Reduces address overlap occurrence.", "opta": "1, 3 and 4", "optb": "3, 5 and 6", "optc": "5 and 6", "optd": "2, 4 and 6", "ans": "D", "explanation": "NAT is not perfect, but there are some advantages. It conserves global addresses, which allow us to add millions of hosts to the Internet without \"real\" IP addresses. This provides flexibility in our corporate networks. NAT can also allow you to use the same subnet more than once in the same network without overlapping networks."}, {"question": "Which of the following is considered to be the address before translation?", "opta": "Inside local", "optb": "Outside local", "optc": "Inside global", "optd": "Outside global", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The host on the private network before translation is considered to be an inside local host."}, {"question": "Which of the following are disadvantages of using NAT?\n  Translation introduces switching path delays.\n  Conserves legally registered addresses.\n  Causes loss of end-to-end IP traceability.\n  Increases flexibility when connecting to the Internet.\n  Certain applications will not function with NAT enabled.\n  Reduces address overlap occurrence.", "opta": "1, 3 and 5", "optb": "3 and 4", "optc": "2, 4 and 5", "optd": "1 and 3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "NAT is not perfect and can cause some issues in some networks, but most networks work just fine. NAT can cause delays and troubleshooting problems, and some applications just won't work."}, {"question": "Which of the following is considered to be the destination host after translation?", "opta": "Inside local", "optb": "Outside local", "optc": "Inside global", "optd": "Outside global", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The host on the global network after translation is considered to be an outside global host."}, {"question": "Which command will create a dynamic pool named Todd that will provide you with 30 global addresses?", "opta": "ip nat pool Todd 171.16.10.65 171.16.10.94 net 255.255.255.240", "optb": "ip nat pool Todd 171.16.10.65 171.16.10.94 net 255.255.255.224", "optc": "ip nat pool todd 171.16.10.65 171.16.10.94 net 255.255.255.224", "optd": "ip nat pool Todd 171.16.10.1 171.16.10.254 net 255.255.255.0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The command ip nat pool <name> creates the pool that hosts can use to get onto the global Internet. What makes option B correct is that the range 171.16.10.65 through 171.16.10.94 includes 30 hosts, but the mask has to match 30 hosts as well, and that mask is 255.255.255.224. Option C is wrong because the pool name has a lower case \"T\" in the pool name. Pool name's are case sensitive."}, {"question": "Which command will clear all the translations active on your router?", "opta": "show ip nat translations", "optb": "show ip nat statistics", "optc": "debug ip nat", "optd": "clear ip nat translations *", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The command clear ip nat translations * will clear all the active NAT entries in your translation table."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true regarding access lists applied to an interface?", "opta": "You can place as many access lists as you want on any interface until you run out of memory.", "optb": "You can apply only one access list on any interface.", "optc": "One access list may be configured, per direction, for each layer 3 protocol configured on an interface.", "optd": "You can apply two access lists to any interface.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A Cisco router has rules regarding the placement of access lists on a router interface. You can place one access list per direction for each layer 3 protocol configured on an interface."}, {"question": "Which command would you use to apply an access list to a router interface?", "opta": "ip access-list 101 out", "optb": "access-list ip 101 in", "optc": "ip access-group 101 in", "optd": "access-group ip 101 in", "ans": "C", "explanation": "To apply an access list, the proper command is ip access-group 101 in."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an example of a standard IP access list?", "opta": "access-list 110 permit host 1.1.1.1", "optb": "access-list 1 deny 172.16.10.1 0.0.0.0", "optc": "access-list 1 permit 172.16.10.1 255.255.0.0", "optd": "access-list standard 1.1.1.1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Standard IP access lists use the numbers 1-99 and 1300-1999 and filter based on source IP address only. Option C is incorrect because the mask must be in wildcard format."}, {"question": "You need to create an access list that will prevent hosts in the network range of 192.168.160.0 to 192.168.191.0. Which of the following lists will you use?", "opta": "access-list 10 deny 192.168.160.0 255.255.224.0", "optb": "access-list 10 deny 192.168.160.0 0.0.191.255", "optc": "access-list 10 deny 192.168.160.0 0.0.31.255", "optd": "access-list 10 deny 192.168.0.0 0.0.31.255", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The range of 192.168.160.0 to 192.168.191.0 is a block size of 32. The network address is 192.168.160.0 and the mask would be 255.255.224.0, which for an access list must be a wildcard format of 0.0.31.255. The 31 is used for a block size of 32. The wildcard is always one less than the block size."}, {"question": "You are working on a router that has established privilege levels that restrict access to certain functions. You discover that you are not able to execute the command show running-configuration. How can you view and confirm the access lists that have been applied to the Ethernet 0 interface on your router?", "opta": "show access-lists", "optb": "show interface Ethernet 0", "optc": "show ip access-lists", "optd": "show ip interface Ethernet 0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The only command that shows which access lists have been applied to an interface is show ip interface Ethernet 0. The command show access-lists displays all configured access lists, and show ip access-lists displays all configured IP access lists, but neither command indicates whether the displayed access lists have been applied to an interface."}, {"question": "What command will permit SMTP mail to only host 1.1.1.1?", "opta": "access-list 10 permit smtp host 1.1.1.1", "optb": "access-list 110 permit ip smtp host 1.1.1.1", "optc": "access-list 10 permit tcp any host 1.1.1.1 eq smtp", "optd": "access-list 110 permit tcp any host 1.1.1.1 eq smtp", "ans": "D", "explanation": "When trying to find the best answer to an access-list question, always check the access-list number and then the protocol. When filtering to an upper-layer protocol, you must use an extended list, numbers 100-199 and 2000-2699. Also, when you filter to an upper-layer protocol, you must use either tcp or udp in the protocol field. If it says ip in the protocol field, you cannot filter to an upper-layer protocol. SMTP uses TCP."}, {"question": "You want to create a standard access list that denies the subnet of the following host: 172.16.50.172/20. Which of the following would you start your list with?", "opta": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.48.0 255.255.240.0", "optb": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.0.0 0.0.255.255", "optc": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.64.0 0.0.31.255", "optd": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.48.0 0.0.15.255", "ans": "D", "explanation": "First, you must know that a /20 is 255.255.240.0, which is a block size of 16 in the third octet. Counting by 16s, this makes our subnet 48 in the third octet, and the wildcard for the third octet would be 15 since the wildcard is always one less than the block size."}, {"question": "What router command allows you to determine whether an IP access list is enabled on a particular interface?", "opta": "show ip port", "optb": "show access-lists", "optc": "show ip interface", "optd": "show access-lists interface", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Only the show ip interface command will tell you which interfaces have access lists applied. show access-lists will not show you which interfaces have an access list applied."}, {"question": "You have created a named access list called Blocksales. Which of the following is a valid command for applying this to packets trying to enter interface s0 of your router?", "opta": "(config)# ip access-group 110 in", "optb": "(config-if)# ip access-group 110 in", "optc": "(config-if)# ip access-group Blocksales in", "optd": "(config-if)# blocksales ip access-list in", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Using a named access list just replaces the number used when applying the list to the router's interface. ip access-group Blocksales in is correct."}, {"question": "You want to create a standard access list that denies the subnet of the following host: 172.16.144.17/21. Which of the following would you start your list with?", "opta": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.48.0 255.255.240.0", "optb": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.144.0 0.0.7.255", "optc": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.64.0 0.0.31.255", "optd": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.136.0 0.0.15.255", "ans": "B", "explanation": "First, you must know that a /21 is 255.255.248.0, which is a block size of 8 in the third octet. Counting by eight, this makes our subnet 144 in the third octet, and the wildcard for the third octet would be 7 since the wildcard is always one less than the block size."}, {"question": "You configure the following access list:\naccess-list 110 deny tcp 10.1.1.128 0.0.0.63 any eq smtp\naccess-list 110 deny tcp any eq 23\nint ethernet 0\nip access-group 110 out\nWhat will the result of this access list be?", "opta": "Email and Telnet will be allowed out E0.", "optb": "Email and Telnet will be allowed in E0.", "optc": "Everything but email and Telnet will be allowed out E0.", "optd": "No IP traffic will be allowed out E0.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "If you add an access list to an interface and you do not have at least one permit statement, then you will effectively shut down the interface because of the implicit deny any at the end of every list."}, {"question": "You want to create a standard access list that denies the subnet of the following host: 172.16.198.94/19. Which of the following would you start your list with?", "opta": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.192.0 0.0.31.255", "optb": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.0.0 0.0.255.255", "optc": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.172.0 0.0.31.255", "optd": "access-list 10 deny 172.16.188.0 0.0.15.255", "ans": "A", "explanation": "First, you must know that a /19 is 255.255.224.0, which is a block size of 32 in the third octet. Counting by 32, this makes our subnet 192 in the third octet, and the wildcard for the third octet would be 31 since the wildcard is always one less than the block size."}, {"question": "If you wanted to deny all Telnet connections to only network 192.168.10.0, which command could you use?", "opta": "access-list 100 deny tcp 192.168.10.0 255.255.255.0 eq telnet", "optb": "access-list 100 deny tcp 192.168.10.0 0.255.255.255 eq telnet", "optc": "access-list 100 deny tcp any 192.168.10.0 0.0.0.255 eq 23", "optd": "access-list 100 deny 192.168.10.0 0.0.0.255 any eq 23", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The extended access list ranges are 100-199 and 2000-2699, so the access-list number of 100 is valid. Telnet uses TCP, so the protocol TCP is valid. Now you just need to look for the source and destination address. Only the third option has the correct sequence of parameters. Answer B may work, but the question specifically states \"only\" to network 192.168.10.0, and the wildcard in answer B is too broad."}, {"question": "Which router command allows you to view the entire contents of all access lists?", "opta": "Router# show interface", "optb": "Router> show ip interface", "optc": "Router# show access-lists", "optd": "Router> show all access-lists", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The show access-lists command will allow you to view the entire contents of all access lists, but it will not show you the interfaces to which the access lists are applied."}, {"question": "Which of the following access lists will allow only HTTP traffic into network 196.15.7.0?", "opta": "access-list 100 permit tcp any 196.15.7.0 0.0.0.255 eq www", "optb": "access-list 10 deny tcp any 196.15.7.0 eq www", "optc": "access-list 100 permit 196.15.7.0 0.0.0.255 eq www", "optd": "access-list 110 permit ip any 196.15.7.0 0.0.0.255", "opte": "access-list 110 permit www 196.15.7.0 0.0.0.255", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The first thing to check in a question like this is the access-list number. Right away, you can see that the second option is wrong because it is using a standard IP access-list number. The second thing to check is the protocol. If you are filtering by upper-layer protocol, then you must be using either UDP or TCP; this eliminates the fourth option. The third and last answers have the wrong syntax."}, {"question": "Which of the following are valid ways to refer only to host 172.16.30.55 in an IP access list?\n  172.16.30.55 0.0.0.255\n  172.16.30.55 0.0.0.0\n  any 172.16.30.55\n  host 172.16.30.55\n  0.0.0.0 172.16.30.55\n  ip any 172.16.30.55", "opta": "1 and 4", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "1, 4 and 6", "optd": "3 and 5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The wildcard 0.0.0.0 tells the router to match all four octets. This wildcard format alone can be replaced with the host command."}, {"question": "If you wanted to deny FTP access from network 200.200.10.0 to network 200.199.11.0 but allow everything else, which of the following command strings is valid?", "opta": "access-list 110 deny 200.200.10.0 to network 200.199.11.0 eq ftp\naccess-list 111 permit ip any 0.0.0.0 255.255.255.255", "optb": "access-list 1 deny ftp 200.200.10.0 200.199.11.0 any any", "optc": "access-list 100 deny tcp 200.200.10.0 0.0.0.255 200.199.11.0 0.0.0.255 eq ftp", "optd": "access-list 198 deny tcp 200.200.10.0 0.0.0.255 200.199.11.0 0.0.0.255 eq ftp\naccess-list 198 permit ip any 0.0.0.0 255.255.255.255", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Extended IP access lists use numbers 100-199 and 2000-2699 and filter based on source and destination IP address, protocol number, and port number. The last option is correct because of the second line that specifies permit ip any any. (I used 0.0.0.0 255.255.255.255, which is the same as the any option.) The third option does not have this, so it would deny access but not allow everything else."}, {"question": "Which of the following series of commands will restrict Telnet access to the router?", "opta": "Lab_A(config)#access-list 10 permit 172.16.1.1\nLab_A(config)#line con 0\nLab_A(config-line)#ip access-group 10 in", "optb": "Lab_A(config)#access-list 10 permit 172.16.1.1\nLab_A(config)#line vty 0 4\nLab_A(config-line)#access-class 10 out", "optc": "Lab_A(config)#access-list 10 permit 172.16.1.1\nLab_A(config)#line vty 0 4\nLab_A(config-line)#access-class 10 in", "optd": "Lab_A(config)#access-list 10 permit 172.16.1.1\nLab_A(config)#line vty 0 4\nLab_A(config-line)#ip access-group 10 in", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Telnet access to the router is restricted by using either a standard or extended IP access list inbound on the VTY lines of the router. The command access-class is used to apply the access list to the VTY lines."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands connect access list 110 inbound to interface ethernet0?", "opta": "Router(config)# ip access-group 110 in", "optb": "Router(config)# ip access-list 110 in", "optc": "Router(config-if)# ip access-group 110 in", "optd": "Router(config-if)# ip access-list 110 in", "ans": "C", "explanation": "To place an access list on an interface, use the ip access-group command in interface configuration mode."}, {"question": "What is the purpose of Spanning Tree Protocol in a switched LAN?", "opta": "To provide a mechanism for network monitoring in switched environments", "optb": "To prevent routing loops in networks with redundant paths", "optc": "To prevent switching loops in networks with redundant switched paths", "optd": "To manage the VLAN database across multiple switches", "opte": "To create collision domains", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The Spanning Tree Protocol (STP) was designed to stop layer 2 loops. All Cisco switches have the STP on by default."}, {"question": "Which statement describes a spanning-tree network that has converged?", "opta": "All switch and bridge ports are in the forwarding state.", "optb": "All switch and bridge ports are assigned as either root or designated ports.", "optc": "All switch and bridge ports are in either the forwarding or blocking state.", "optd": "All switch and bridge ports are either blocking or looping.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Convergence occurs when all ports on bridges and switches have transitioned to either the forwarding or blocking states. No data is forwarded until convergence is complete. Before data can be forwarded again, all devices must be updated."}, {"question": "What does a switch do when a frame is received on an interface and the destination hardware address is unknown or not in the filter table?", "opta": "Forwards the switch to the first available link", "optb": "Drops the frame", "optc": "Floods the network with the frame looking for the device", "optd": "Sends back a message to the originating station asking for a name resolution", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Switches flood all frames that have an unknown destination address. If a device answers the frame, the switch will update the MAC address table to reflect the location of the device."}, {"question": "In which circumstance are multiple copies of the same unicast frame likely to be transmitted in a switched LAN?", "opta": "During high-traffic periods", "optb": "After broken links are reestablished", "optc": "When upper-layer protocols require high reliability", "optd": "In an improperly implemented redundant topology", "ans": "D", "explanation": "If the Spanning Tree Protocol is not running on your switches and you connect them together with redundant links, you will have broadcast storms and multiple frame copies."}, {"question": "If you want to disable STP on a port connected to a server, which command would you use?", "opta": "disable spanning-tree", "optb": "spanning-tree off", "optc": "spanning-tree security", "optd": "spanning-tree portfast", "ans": "D", "explanation": "If you have a server or other devices connected into your switch that you're totally sure won't create a switching loop if STP is disabled, you can use something called portfast on these ports. Using it means the port won't spend the usual 50 seconds to come up while STP is converging."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is true?", "opta": "A switch creates a single collision domain and a single broadcast domain. A router creates a single collision domain.", "optb": "A switch creates separate collision domains but one broadcast domain. A router provides a separate broadcast domain.", "optc": "A switch creates a single collision domain and separate broadcast domains. A router provides a separate broadcast domain as well.", "optd": "A switch creates separate collision domains and separate broadcast domains. A router provides separate collision domains.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Switches break up collision domains, and routers break up broadcast domains."}, {"question": "You have two switches connected together with two crossover cables for redundancy, and STP is disabled. Which of the following will happen between the switches?", "opta": "The routing tables on the switches will not update.", "optb": "The MAC forward/filter table will not update on the switch.", "optc": "Broadcast storms will occur on the switched network.", "optd": "The switches will automatically load-balance between the two links.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "If spanning tree is disabled on a switch and you have redundant links to another switch, broadcast storms will occur, among other possible problems."}, {"question": "Layer 2 switching provides which of the following?\n  Hardware-based bridging (ASIC)\n  Wire speed\n  Low latency\n  Low cost", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "1, 2 and 4", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Switches, unlike bridges, are hardware based. Cisco says its switches are wire speed and provide low latency, and I guess they are low cost compared to their prices in the 1990s."}, {"question": "Your switch has a port status LED that is alternating between green and amber. What could this indicate?", "opta": "The port is experiencing errors.", "optb": "The port is shut down.", "optc": "The port is in STP blocking mode.", "optd": "Nothing; this is normal.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "When you connect to a switch port, at first the link lights are orange/amber, and then they turn green, indicating normal operation. If the link light is blinking, you have a problem."}, {"question": "You want to run the new 802.1w on your switches. Which of the following would enable this protocol?", "opta": "Switch(config)# spanning-tree mode rapid-pvst", "optb": "Switch# spanning-tree mode rapid-pvst", "optc": "Switch(config)# spanning-tree mode 802.1w", "optd": "Switch# spanning-tree mode 802.1w", "ans": "A", "explanation": "802.1w is the also called Rapid Spanning Tree Protocol. It is not enabled by default on Cisco switches, but it is a better STP to run since it has all the fixes that the Cisco extensions provide with 802.1d."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a layer 2 protocol used to maintain a loop-free network?", "opta": "VTP", "optb": "STP", "optc": "RIP", "optd": "CDP", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The Spanning Tree Protocol is used to stop switching loops in a switched network with redundant paths."}, {"question": "You need to allow one host to be permitted to attach dynamically to each switch interface. Which two commands must you configure on your catalyst switch to meet this policy?\n  Switch(config-if)# ip access-group 10\n  Switch(config-if)# switchport port-security maximum 1\n  Switch(config)# access-list 10 permit ip host 1\n  Switch(config-if)# switchport port-security violation shutdown\n  Switch(config)# mac-address-table secure", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "2, 3 and 5", "optd": "4 and 5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The switchport port-security is an important command, and it's super easy with the CNA; however, from the CLI, you can set the maximum number of MAC addresses allowed into the port, and then set the penalty if this maximum has been passed."}, {"question": "What command will display the forward/filter table?", "opta": "show mac filter", "optb": "show run", "optc": "show mac address-table", "optd": "show mac filter-table", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The command show mac address-table displays the forward/filter table on the switch."}, {"question": "If a switch receives a frame and the source MAC address is not in the MAC address table but the destination address is, what will the switch do with the frame?", "opta": "Discard it and send an error message back to the originating host", "optb": "Flood the network with the frame", "optc": "Add the source address and port to the MAC address table and forward the frame out the destination port", "optd": "Add the destination to the MAC address table and then forward the frame", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Since the source MAC address is not in the MAC address table, the switch will add the source address and the port it is connected to into the MAC address table and then forward the frame to the outgoing port."}, {"question": "What is the result of segmenting a network with a bridge (switch)?\n  It increases the number of collision domains.\n  It decreases the number of collision domains.\n  It increases the number of broadcast domains.\n  It decreases the number of broadcast domains.\n  It makes smaller collision domains.\n  It makes larger collision domains.", "opta": "1 and 5", "optb": "2, 3 and 5", "optc": "3, 4 and 6", "optd": "1, 3 and 6", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Bridges break up collision domains, which would increase the number of collision domains in a network and also make smaller collision domains."}, {"question": "What are the distinct functions of layer 2 switching that increase available bandwidth on the network?\n  Address learning\n  Routing\n  Forwarding and filtering\n  Creating network loops\n  Loop avoidance\n  IP addressing", "opta": "1, 3 and 5", "optb": "2, 4 and 6", "optc": "2 and 6", "optd": "3 and 5", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Layer 2 features include address learning, forwarding and filtering of the network, and loop avoidance."}, {"question": "Your router has the following IP address on Ethernet0: 172.16.2.1/23. Which of the following can be valid host IDs on the LAN interface attached to the router?\n  172.16.1.100\n  172.16.1.198\n  172.16.2.255\n  172.16.3.0", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "2 and 3 only", "optc": "3 and 4 only", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The router's IP address on the E0 interface is 172.16.2.1/23, which is 255.255.254.0. This makes the third octet a block size of 2. The router's interface is in the 2.0 subnet, and the broadcast address is 3.255 because the next subnet is 4.0. The valid host range is 2.1 through 3.254. The router is using the first valid host address in the range."}, {"question": "Which two statements describe the IP address 10.16.3.65/23?\n  The subnet address is 10.16.3.0 255.255.254.0.\n  The lowest host address in the subnet is 10.16.2.1 255.255.254.0.\n  The last valid host address in the subnet is 10.16.2.254 255.255.254.0.\n  The broadcast address of the subnet is 10.16.3.255 255.255.254.0.", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "1, 2 and 4", "optd": "2, 3 and 4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The mask 255.255.254.0 (/23) used with a Class A address means that there are 15 subnet bits and 9 host bits. The block size in the third octet is 2 (256 - 254). So this makes the subnets in the interesting octet 0, 2, 4, 6, etc., all the way to 254. The host 10.16.3.65 is in the 2.0 subnet. The next subnet is 4.0, so the broadcast address for the 2.0 subnet is 3.255. The valid host addresses are 2.1 through 3.254."}, {"question": "A network administrator is connecting hosts A and B directly through their Ethernet interfaces, as shown in the illustration. Ping attempts between the hosts are unsuccessful. What can be \ndone to provide connectivity between the hosts?\n\n  A crossover cable should be used in place of the straight-through cable.\n  A rollover cable should be used in place of the straight-through cable.\n  The subnet masks should be set to 255.255.255.192.\n  A default gateway needs to be set on each host.\n  The subnet masks should be set to 255.255.255.0.", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "2 only", "optc": "3 and 4 only", "optd": "1 and 5 only", "opte": "2 and 5 only", "ans": "D", "explanation": "First, if you have two hosts directly connected, as shown in the graphic, then you need \na crossover cable. A straight-through cable won't work. Second, the hosts have different \nmasks, which puts them in different subnets. The easy solution is just to set both masks to \n255.255.255.0 (/24)."}, {"question": "What is the maximum number of IP addresses that can be assigned to hosts on a local subnet that uses the 255.255.255.224 subnet mask?", "opta": "14", "optb": "15", "optc": "16", "optd": "30", "ans": "D", "explanation": "A /27 (255.255.255.224) is 3 bits on and 5 bits off. This provides 8 subnets, each with 30 hosts. Does it matter if this mask is used with a Class A, B, or C network address? Not at all. The number of host bits would never change."}, {"question": "You need to subnet a network that has 5 subnets, each with at least 16 hosts. Which classful subnet mask would you use?", "opta": "255.255.255.192", "optb": "255.255.255.224", "optc": "255.255.255.240", "optd": "255.255.255.248", "ans": "B", "explanation": "You need 5 subnets, each with at least 16 hosts. The mask 255.255.255.240 provides 16 subnets with 14 hosts-this will not work. The mask 255.255.255.224 provides 8 subnets, each with 30 hosts. This is the best answer."}, {"question": "You have a network that needs 29 subnets while maximizing the number of host addresses available on each subnet. How many bits must you borrow from the host field to provide the correct subnet mask?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "A 240 mask is 4 subnet bits and provides 16 subnets, each with 14 hosts. We need more subnets, so let's add subnet bits. One more subnet bit would be a 248 mask. This provides 5 subnet bits (32 subnets) with 3 host bits (6 hosts per subnet). This is the best answer."}, {"question": "If an Ethernet port on a router were assigned an IP address of 172.16.112.1/25, what would be the valid subnet address of this host?", "opta": "172.16.112.0", "optb": "172.16.0.0", "optc": "172.16.96.0", "optd": "172.16.255.0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "A /25 mask is 255.255.255.128. Used with a Class B network, the third and fourth octets are used for subnetting with a total of 9 subnet bits, 8 bits in the third octet and 1 bit in the fourth octet. Since there is only 1 bit in the fourth octet, the bit is either off or on-which is a value of 0 or 128. The host in the question is in the 0 subnet, which has a broadcast address of 127 since 128 is the next subnet."}, {"question": "You have an interface on a router with the IP address of 192.168.192.10/29. Including the router interface, how many hosts can have IP addresses on the LAN attached to the router interface?", "opta": "6", "optb": "8", "optc": "30", "optd": "32", "ans": "A", "explanation": "A /29 (255.255.255.248), regardless of the class of address, has only 3 host bits. Six hosts is the maximum number of hosts on this LAN, including the router interface."}, {"question": "What is the subnetwork number of a host with an IP address of 172.16.66.0/21?", "opta": "172.16.36.0", "optb": "172.16.48.0", "optc": "172.16.64.0", "optd": "172.16.0.0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A /21 is 255.255.248.0, which means we have a block size of 8 in the third octet, so we just count by 8 until we reach 66. The subnet in this question is 64.0. The next subnet is 72.0, so the broadcast address of the 64 subnet is 71.255."}, {"question": "The network address of 172.16.0.0/19 provides how many subnets and hosts?", "opta": "7 subnets, 30 hosts each", "optb": "8 subnets, 8,190 hosts each", "optc": "8 subnets, 2,046 hosts each", "optd": "7 subnets, 2,046 hosts each", "ans": "B", "explanation": "A CIDR address of /19 is 255.255.224.0. This is a Class B address, so that is only 3 subnet bits, but it provides 13 host bits, or 8 subnets, each with 8,190 hosts."}, {"question": "You need to configure a server that is on the subnet 192.168.19.24/29. The router has the first available host address. Which of the following should you assign to the server?", "opta": "192.168.19.0 255.255.255.0", "optb": "192.168.19.33 255.255.255.240", "optc": "192.168.19.26 255.255.255.248", "optd": "192.168.19.31 255.255.255.248", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A /29 is 255.255.255.248, which is a block size of 8 in the fourth octet. The subnets are 0, 8, 16, 24, 32, 40, etc. 192.168.19.24 is the 24 subnet, and since 32 is the next subnet, the broadcast address for the 24 subnet is 31. 192.168.19.26 is the only correct answer."}, {"question": "You have an interface on a router with the IP address of 192.168.192.10/29. What is the broadcast address the hosts will use on this LAN?", "opta": "192.168.192.15", "optb": "192.168.192.31", "optc": "192.168.192.63", "optd": "192.168.192.127", "ans": "A", "explanation": "A /29 (255.255.255.248) has a block size of 8 in the fourth octet. This means the subnets are 0, 8, 16, 24, etc. 10 is in the 8 subnet. The next subnet is 16, so 15 is the broadcast address."}, {"question": "You have a network with a subnet of 172.16.17.0/22. Which is the valid host address?", "opta": "172.16.17.1 255.255.255.252", "optb": "172.16.0.1 255.255.240.0", "optc": "172.16.20.1 255.255.254.0", "optd": "172.16.18.255 255.255.252.0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "A Class B network ID with a /22 mask is 255.255.252.0, with a block size of 4 in the third octet. The network address in the question is in subnet 172.16.16.0 with a broadcast address of 172.16.19.255. Only option E even has the correct subnet mask listed, and 172.16.18.255 is a valid host."}, {"question": "On a VLSM network, which mask should you use on point-to-point WAN links in order to reduce the waste of IP addresses?", "opta": "/27", "optb": "/28", "optc": "/29", "optd": "/30", "ans": "D", "explanation": "A point-to-point link uses only two hosts. A /30, or 255.255.255.252, mask provides two hosts per subnet."}, {"question": "To test the IP stack on your local host, which IP address would you ping?", "opta": "127.0.0.0", "optb": "1.0.0.127", "optc": "127.0.0.1", "optd": "127.0.0.255", "ans": "C", "explanation": "To test the local stack on your host, ping the loopback interface of 127.0.0.1."}, {"question": "If a host on a network has the address 172.16.45.14/30, what is the subnetwork this host belongs to?", "opta": "172.16.45.0", "optb": "172.16.45.4", "optc": "172.16.45.8", "optd": "172.16.45.12", "ans": "D", "explanation": "A /30, regardless of the class of address, has a 252 in the fourth octet. This means we have a block size of 4 and our subnets are 0, 4, 8, 12, 16, etc. Address 14 is obviously in the 12 subnet."}, {"question": "Using the following illustration, what would be the IP address of E0 if you were using the eighth subnet? The network ID is 192.168.10.0/28 and you need to use the last available IP \naddress in the range. The zero subnet should not be considered valid for this question.", "opta": "192.168.10.142", "optb": "192.168.10.66", "optc": "192.168.100.254", "optd": "192.168.10.143", "opte": "192.168.10.126", "ans": "A", "explanation": "A /28 is a 255.255.255.240 mask. Let's count to the ninth subnet (we need to find the \nbroadcast address of the eighth subnet, so we need to count to the ninth subnet). Starting at 16 \n(remember, the question stated that we will not use subnet zero, so we start at 16, not 0), 16, \n32, 48, 64, 80, 96, 112, 128, 144. The eighth subnet is 128 and the next subnet is 144, so our \nbroadcast address of the 128 subnet is 143. This makes the host range 129-142. 142 is the last \nvalid host."}, {"question": "Which configuration command must be in effect to allow the use of 8 subnets if the Class C subnet mask is 255.255.255.224?", "opta": "Router(config)#ip classless", "optb": "Router(config)#no ip classful", "optc": "Router(config)#ip unnumbered", "optd": "Router(config)#ip subnet-zero", "ans": "D", "explanation": "A Class C subnet mask of 255.255.255.224 is 3 bits on and 5 bits off (11100000) and provides 8 subnets, each with 30 hosts. However, if the command ip subnet-zero is not used, then only 6 subnets would be available for use."}, {"question": "Using the illustration from the previous question, what would be the IP address of S0 if you were using the first subnet? The network ID is 192.168.10.0/28 and you need to use the last available IP address in the range. Again, the zero subnet should not be considered valid for this question.", "opta": "192.168.10.24", "optb": "192.168.10.62", "optc": "192.168.10.30", "optd": "192.168.10.127", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A /28 is a 255.255.255.240 mask. The first subnet is 16 (remember that the question stated not to use subnet zero) and the next subnet is 32, so our broadcast address is 31. This makes our host range 17-30. 30 is the last valid host."}, {"question": "What is the subnetwork address for a host with the IP address 200.10.5.68/28?", "opta": "200.10.5.56", "optb": "200.10.5.32", "optc": "200.10.5.64", "optd": "200.10.5.0", "ans": "C", "explanation": "This is a pretty simple question. A /28 is 255.255.255.240, which means that our block size is 16 in the fourth octet. 0, 16, 32, 48, 64, 80, etc. The host is in the 64 subnet."}, {"question": "Which of the following services use TCP? \n  DHCP\n  SMTP\n  HTTP\n  TFTP\n  FTP", "opta": "1 and 2", "optb": "2, 3 and 5", "optc": "1, 2 and 4", "optd": "1, 3 and 4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "SMTP, HTTP and FTP use TCP."}, {"question": "What layer in the TCP/IP stack is equivalent to the Transport layer of the OSI model?", "opta": "Application", "optb": "Host-to-Host", "optc": "Internet", "optd": "Network Access", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The four layers of the TCP/IP stack (also called the DoD model) are Application/Process, Host-to-Host, Internet, and Network Access. The Host-to-Host layer is equivalent to the Transport layer of the OSI model."}, {"question": "Which of the following describe the DHCP Discover message?\n  It uses FF:FF:FF:FF:FF:FF as a layer 2 broadcast.\n  It uses UDP as the Transport layer protocol.\n  It uses TCP as the Transport layer protocol.\n  It does not use a layer 2 destination address.", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "1 and 2", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "4 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "A client that sends out a DHCP Discover message in order to receive an IP address sends out a broadcast at both layer 2 and layer 3. The layer 2 broadcast is all Fs in hex, or FF:FF:FF:FF:FF:FF. The layer 3 broadcast is 255.255.255.255, which means all networks and all hosts. DHCP is connectionless, which means it uses User Datagram Protocol (UDP) at the Transport layer, also called the Host-to-Host layer."}, {"question": "You want to implement a mechanism that automates the IP configuration, including IP address, subnet mask, default gateway, and DNS information. Which protocol will you use to accomplish this?", "opta": "SMTP", "optb": "SNMP", "optc": "DHCP", "optd": "ARP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) is used to provide IP information to hosts on your network. DHCP can provide a lot of information, but the most common is IP address, subnet mask, default gateway, and DNS information."}, {"question": "Which of the following is private IP address?", "opta": "12.0.0.1", "optb": "168.172.19.39", "optc": "172.15.14.36", "optd": "192.168.24.43", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Class A private address range is 10.0.0.0 through 10.255.255.255. Class B private address range is 172.16.0.0 through 172.31.255.255, and Class C private address range is 192.168.0.0 through 192.168.255.255."}, {"question": "Which of the following allows a router to respond to an ARP request that is intended for a remote host?", "opta": "Gateway DP", "optb": "Reverse ARP (RARP)", "optc": "Proxy ARP", "optd": "Inverse ARP (IARP)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Proxy ARP can help machines on a subnet reach remote subnets without configuring routing or a default gateway."}, {"question": "The DoD model (also called the TCP/IP stack) has four layers. Which layer of the DoD model is equivalent to the Network layer of the OSI model?", "opta": "Application", "optb": "Host-to-Host", "optc": "Internet", "optd": "Network Access", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The four layers of the DoD model are Application/Process, Host-to-Host, Internet, and Network Access. The Internet layer is equivalent to the Network layer of the OSI model."}, {"question": "Which of the following services use UDP?\n  DHCP\n  SMTP\n  SNMP\n  FTP\n  HTTP\n  TFTP", "opta": "1, 3 and 6", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "1, 2 and 4", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "DHCP, SNMP, and TFTP use UDP."}, {"question": "Which class of IP address provides a maximum of only 254 host addresses per network ID?", "opta": "Class A", "optb": "Class B", "optc": "Class C", "optd": "Class D", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A Class C network address has only 8 bits for defining hosts: 28 - 2 = 254."}, {"question": "If you use either Telnet or FTP, which is the highest layer you are using to transmit data?", "opta": "Application", "optb": "Presentation", "optc": "Session", "optd": "Transport", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Both FTP and Telnet use TCP at the Transport layer; however, they both are Application layer protocols, so the Application layer is the best answer."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the decimal and hexadecimal equivalents of the binary number 10011101?", "opta": "155, 0x9B", "optb": "157, 0x9D", "optc": "159, 0x9F", "optd": "185, 0xB9", "ans": "B", "explanation": "To turn a binary number into decimal, you just have to add the values of each bit that is a 1. The values of 10011101 are 128, 16, 8, 4, and 1. 128 + 16 + 8 + 4 + 1 = 157.\nHexadecimal is a base-16 number system. The values of hexadecimal are 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, A, B, C, D, E, F-16 characters total, from which to create all the numbers you'll ever need. So, if 1001 in binary is 9, then the hexadecimal equivalent is 9. Since we then have 1101, which is 13 in binary, the hexadecimal answer is D and the complete hexadecimal answer is 0x9D."}, {"question": "Which statements are true regarding ICMP packets?\n  They acknowledge receipt of a TCP segment.\n  They guarantee datagram delivery.\n  They can provide hosts with information about network problems.\n  They are encapsulated within IP datagrams.", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "2 and 3", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "2, 3 and 4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Internet Control Message Protocol (ICMP) is used to send error messages through the network, but they do not work alone. Every segment or ICMP payload must be encapsulated within an IP datagram (or packet)."}, {"question": "Which of the following are layers in the TCP/IP model?\n  Application\n  Session\n  Transport\n  Internet\n  Data Link\n  Physical", "opta": "1 and 2", "optb": "1, 3 and 4", "optc": "2, 3 and 5", "optd": "3, 4 and 5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "This seems like a hard question at first because it doesn't make sense. The listed answers are from the OSI model and the question asked about the TCP/IP protocol stack (DoD model). However, let's just look for what is wrong. First, the Session layer is not in the TCP/IP model; neither are the Data Link and Physical layers. This leaves us with the Transport layer (Host-to-Host in the DoD model), Internet layer (Network layer in the OSI), and Application layer (Application/Process in the DoD)."}, {"question": "Which layer 4 protocol is used for a Telnet connection?", "opta": "IP", "optb": "TCP", "optc": "TCP/IP", "optd": "UDP", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Although Telnet does use TCP and IP (TCP/IP), the question specifically asks about layer 4, and IP works at layer 3. Telnet uses TCP at layer 4."}, {"question": "Which statements are true regarding ICMP packets?\n  ICMP guarantees datagram delivery.\n  ICMP can provide hosts with information about network problems.\n  ICMP is encapsulated within IP datagrams.\n  ICMP is encapsulated within UDP datagrams.", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "2 and 3", "optc": "1 and 4", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "ICMP is used for diagnostics and destination unreachable messages. ICMP is encapsulated within IP datagrams, and because it is used for diagnostics, it will provide hosts with information about network problems."}, {"question": "Which of the following are TCP/IP protocols used at the Application layer of the OSI model? \n  IP\n  TCP\n  Telnet\n  FTP\n  TFTP", "opta": "1 and 3", "optb": "1, 3 and 5", "optc": "3, 4 and 5", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Telnet, File Transfer Protocol (FTP), and Trivial FTP (TFTP) are all Application layer protocols. IP is a Network layer protocol. Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) is a Transport layer protocol."}, {"question": "What protocol is used to find the hardware address of a local device?", "opta": "RARP", "optb": "ARP", "optc": "IP", "optd": "ICMP", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) is used to find the hardware address from a known IP address."}, {"question": "Which of the following protocols uses both TCP and UDP?", "opta": "FTP", "optb": "SMTP", "optc": "Telnet", "optd": "DNS", "ans": "D", "explanation": "DNS uses TCP for zone exchanges between servers and UDP when a client is trying to resolve a hostname to an IP address."}, {"question": "What is the address range of a Class B network address in binary?", "opta": "01xxxxxx", "optb": "0xxxxxxx", "optc": "10xxxxxx", "optd": "110xxxxx", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The range of a Class B network address is 128-191. This makes our binary range 10xxxxxx."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true regarding VLANs?", "opta": "You must have at least two VLANs defined in every Cisco switched network.", "optb": "All VLANs are configured at the fastest switch and, by default, propagate this information to all other switches.", "optc": "You should not have more than 10 switches in the same VTP domain.", "optd": "VTP is used to send VLAN information to switches in a configured VTP domain.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Switches do not propagate VLAN information by default; you must configure the VTP domain. VLAN Trunk Protocol (VTP) is used to propagate VLAN information across a trunked link."}, {"question": "Which protocol reduces administrative overhead in a switched network by allowing the configuration of a new VLAN to be distributed to all the switches in a domain?", "opta": "STP", "optb": "VTP", "optc": "DHCP", "optd": "ISL", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Virtual Trunk Protocol (VTP) is used to pass a VLAN database to any or all switches in the switched network. The three VTP modes are server, client, and transparent."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true regarding VTP?", "opta": "All switches are VTP servers by default.", "optb": "All switches are VTP transparent by default.", "optc": "VTP is on by default with a domain name of Cisco on all Cisco switches.", "optd": "All switches are VTP clients by default.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All Cisco switches are VTP servers by default. No other VTP information is configured on a Cisco switch by default. You must set the VTP domain name on all switches to be the same domain name or they will not share the VTP database."}, {"question": "Which of the following commands sets a trunk port on a 2960 switch?", "opta": "trunk on", "optb": "trunk all", "optc": "switchport trunk on", "optd": "switchport mode trunk", "ans": "D", "explanation": "To set a switch port to trunk mode, which allows all VLAN information to pass down the link, use the switchport mode trunk command."}, {"question": "Which command will configure a switch port to use the IEEE standard method of inserting VLAN membership information into Ethernet frames?", "opta": "Switch(config)# switchport trunk encapsulation isl", "optb": "Switch(config)# switchport trunk encapsulation ietf", "optc": "Switch(config)# switchport trunk encapsulation dot1q", "optd": "Switch(config-if)# switchport trunk encapsulation isl", "opte": "Switch(config-if)# switchport trunk encapsulation dot1q", "ans": "E", "explanation": "If you are on a 2950 switch, then the interface command is just switchport mode trunk, since the 2950 can only run the IEEE 802.1Q version. However, a 3550 can run both ISL and 802.1Q, so you must use the encapsulation command. The argument to choose 802.1Q for a trunking protocol is dot1q."}, {"question": "When a new trunk link is configured on an IOS-based switch, which VLANs are allowed over the link?", "opta": "By default, all VLANs are allowed on the trunk.", "optb": "No VLAN's are allowed, you must configure each VLAN by hand.", "optc": "Only configured VLAN's are allowed on the link.", "optd": "Only extended VLAN's are allowed by default.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "By default, all VLANs are allowed on the trunk link and you must remove by hand each VLAN that you don't want traversing the trunked link."}, {"question": "Which of the following modes are valid when a switch port is used as a VLAN trunk?\n  Blocking\n  Dynamic auto\n  Dynamic desirable\n  Nonegotiate\n  Access\n  Learning", "opta": "1, 2 and 6", "optb": "2, 3 and 4", "optc": "4, 5 and 6", "optd": "2, 4, and 5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The valid modes of a VLAN trunk on a switch are dynamic auto, dynamic desirable, trunk (on), and nonegotiate."}, {"question": "To configure the VLAN trunking protocol to communicate VLAN information between two switches, what two requirements must be met?\n  Each end of the trunk link must be set to the IEEE 802.1e encapsulation.\n  The VTP management domain name of both switches must be set the same.\n  All ports on both the switches must be set as access ports.\n  One of the two switches must be configured as a VTP server.\n  A rollover cable is required to connect the two switches together.\n  A router must be used to forward VTP traffic between VLANs.", "opta": "1, 2 and 4", "optb": "3, 5 and 6", "optc": "2 and 4", "optd": "1 and 6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "You must have the same VTP domain name on all switches in order to share VLAN information between the switches. At least one of the switches must be a VTP server; the other switches should be set to VTP client."}, {"question": "You want to improve network performance by increasing the bandwidth available to hosts and limit the size of the broadcast domains. Which of the following options will achieve this goal?", "opta": "Managed hubs", "optb": "Bridges", "optc": "Switches", "optd": "Switches configured with VLANs", "ans": "D", "explanation": "By creating and implementing VLANs in your switched network, you can break up broadcast domains at layer 2. For hosts on different VLANs to communicate, you must have a router or layer 3 switch."}, {"question": "Which switching technology reduces the size of a broadcast domain?", "opta": "ISL", "optb": "802.1Q", "optc": "VLANs", "optd": "STP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Virtual LANs break up broadcast domains in layer 2 switched internetworks."}, {"question": "Which of the following provide inter-switch VLAN communication?\n  ISL\n  VTP\n  802.1Q\n  802.3Z", "opta": "2 only", "optb": "1 and 3", "optc": "2 and 4", "optd": "2, 3 and 4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "ISL is a Cisco-proprietary frame-tagging method. IEEE 802.1Q is the nonproprietary version of frame tagging."}, {"question": "A switch has been configured for three different VLANs: VLAN2, VLAN3, and VLAN4. A router has been added to provide communication between the VLANs. What type of interface is necessary on the router if only one connection is to be made between the router and the switch?", "opta": "10Mbps Ethernet", "optb": "56Kbps Serial", "optc": "100Mbps Ethernet", "optd": "1Gbps Ethernet", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Although you can use either 100Mbps or 1Gbps Ethernet, the 100Mbps is necessary at a minimum and is the best answer to this question. You need to trunk the link from the switch to the router to make this connection work with inter-VLAN communication."}, {"question": "Which of the following are benefits of VLANs?\n  They increase the size of collision domains.\n  They allow logical grouping of users by function.\n  They can enhance network security.\n  They increase the size of broadcast domains while decreasing the number of collision domains.\n  They simplify switch administration.\n  They increase the number of broadcast domains while decreasing the size of the broadcast domains.", "opta": "1 and 5", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "1, 3 and 5", "optd": "2, 3 and 6", "ans": "D", "explanation": "VLANs break up broadcast domains in a switched layer 2 network, which means smaller broadcast domains. They allow configuration by logical function instead of physical location and can create some security if configured correctly."}, {"question": "Which of the following protocols are used to configure trunking on a switch?\n  VLAN Trunk Protocol\n  VLAN\n  802.1Q\n  ISL", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "3 only", "optc": "3 and 4", "optd": "1, 3 and 4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Cisco has a proprietary trunking protocol called ISL. The IEEE version is 802.1Q."}, {"question": "What VTP mode allows you to change VLAN information on the switch?", "opta": "Client", "optb": "STP", "optc": "Server", "optd": "Transparent", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Only in server mode can you change VTP information on a switch."}, {"question": "You connect a host to a switch port, but the new host cannot log into the server that is plugged into the same switch. What could the problem be?", "opta": "The router is not configured for the new host.", "optb": "The VTP configuration on the switch is not updated for the new host.", "optc": "The host has an invalid MAC address.", "optd": "The switch port the host is connected to is not configured to the correct VLAN membership.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "This question is a little vague, but the best answer is that the VLAN membership for the port is not configured."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an IEEE standard for frame tagging?", "opta": "ISL", "optb": "802.3Z", "optc": "802.1Q", "optd": "802.3U", "ans": "C", "explanation": "802.1Q was created to allow trunked links between disparate switches."}, {"question": "When setting up Frame Relay for point-to-point subinterfaces, which of the following must not be configured?", "opta": "The Frame Relay encapsulation on the physical interface", "optb": "The local DLCI on each subinterface", "optc": "An IP address on the physical interface", "optd": "The subinterface type as point-to-point", "ans": "C", "explanation": "It is very important to remember when studying the CCNA exam objectives, and when configuring Frame Relay with point-to-point subinterfaces, that you do not put an IP address on the physical interface."}, {"question": "Which command will display the CHAP authentication process as it occurs between two routers in the network?", "opta": "show chap authentication", "optb": "show interface serial 0", "optc": "debug ppp authentication", "optd": "debug chap authentication", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The command debug ppp authentication will show you the authentication process that PPP uses between point-to-point connections."}, {"question": "The Acme Corporation is implementing dial-up services to enable remote-office employees to connect to the local network. The company uses multiple routed protocols, needs authentication of users connecting to the network, and since some calls will be long distance, needs callback support. Which of the following protocols is the best choice for these remote services?", "opta": "802.1", "optb": "Frame Relay", "optc": "HDLC", "optd": "PPP", "opte": "PAP", "ans": "D", "explanation": "PPP is your only option, as HDLC and Frame Relay do not support these types of business requirements. PPP provides dynamic addressing, authentication using PAP or CHAP, and callback services."}, {"question": "You need to configure a router for a Frame Relay connection to a non-Cisco router. Which of the following commands will prepare the WAN interface of the router for this connection?", "opta": "Router(config-if)#encapsulation frame-relay q933a", "optb": "Router(config-if)#encapsulation frame-relay ansi", "optc": "Router(config-if)#encapsulation frame-relay ietf", "optd": "Router(config-if)#encapsulation frame-relay cisco", "ans": "C", "explanation": "If you have a Cisco router on one side of a Frame Relay network and a non-Cisco router on the other side, you would need to use the Frame Relay encapsulation type of IETF. The default is Cisco encapsulation, which means that a Cisco router must be on both sides of the Frame Relay network."}, {"question": "Which WAN encapsulations can be configured on an asynchronous serial connection?\n  PPP\n  ATM\n  HDLC\n  SDLC\n  Frame Relay", "opta": "1 and 2", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "3, 4 and 5", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Please do not freak out because ATM is an answer to this question. ATM is not covered in depth on the CCNA exam. PPP is mostly used for dial-up (async) services, but ATM could be used as well, though it typically is not used anymore since PPP is so efficient."}, {"question": "Which encapsulations can be configured on a serial interface?\n  Ethernet\n  Token Ring\n  HDLC\n  Frame Relay\n  PPP", "opta": "1 and 4", "optb": "2 only", "optc": "3, 4 and 5", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Ethernet and Token Ring are LAN technologies and cannot be configured on a serial interface. PPP, HDLC, and Frame Relay are layer 2 WAN technologies that are typically configured on a serial interface."}, {"question": "Suppose that you have a customer who has a central HQ and six branch offices. They anticipate adding six more branches in the near future. They wish to implement a WAN technology that will allow the branches to economically connect to HQ and you have no free ports on the HQ router. Which of the following would you recommend?", "opta": "PPP", "optb": "HDLC", "optc": "Frame Relay", "optd": "ISDN", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The key is \"there are no free ports\" on your router. Only Frame Relay can provide a connection to multiple locations with one interface, and in an economical manner no less."}, {"question": "Which of the following command options are displayed when you use the Router# show frame-relay ? command?\n dlci\n neighbors\n lmi\n pvc\n map", "opta": "1 only", "optb": "2 and 4", "optc": "3, 4 and 5", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The show frame-relay ? command provides many options, but the options available in this question are lmi, pvc, and map."}, {"question": "In which of the following technologies is the term HFC used?", "opta": "DSL", "optb": "PPPoE", "optc": "Frame Relay", "optd": "Dedicated T1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "In a modern network, hybrid fibre-coaxial (HFC) is a telecommunications industry term for a network that incorporates both optical fiber and coaxial cable to create a broadband network."}, {"question": "A default Frame Relay WAN is classified as what type of physical network?", "opta": "Point-to-point", "optb": "Broadcast multi-access", "optc": "Non-broadcast multi-access", "optd": "Non-broadcast multipoint", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Frame Relay, by default, is a non-broadcast multi-access (NBMA) network, which means that broadcasts, such as RIP updates, will not be forwarded across the link by default."}, {"question": "Which of the following describes the creation of private networks across the Internet, enabling privacy and tunneling of non-TCP/IP protocols?", "opta": "HDLC", "optb": "Cable", "optc": "VPN", "optd": "IPSec", "opte": "xDSL", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A  allows the creation of private networks across the Internet, enabling privacy and tunneling of non-TCP/IP protocols. A VPN can be set up across any type of link."}, {"question": "Which of the following describes an industry-wide standard suite of protocols and algorithms that allows for secure data transmission over an IP-based network that functions at the layer 3 Network layer of the OSI model?", "opta": "HDLC", "optb": "Cable", "optc": "VPN", "optd": "IPSec", "opte": "xDSL", "ans": "D", "explanation": "IPSec is an industry-wide standard suite of protocols and algorithms that allows for secure data transmission over an IP-based network that functions at the layer 3 Network layer of the OSI model."}, {"question": "Which of the following uses ATM as the Data Link layer protocol that's terminated at what's known as the DSLAM?", "opta": "DSL", "optb": "PPPoE", "optc": "Frame Relay", "optd": "Dedicated T1", "opte": "Wireless", "ans": "A", "explanation": "ATM is the Data-Link layer protocol that's typically used over the DSL layer 1 connection from the CPE and terminated at what's known as the DSLAM-an ATM switch that contains DSL interface cards, or ATU-Cs."}, {"question": "When a router is connected to a Frame Relay WAN link using a serial DTE interface, how is the clock rate determined?", "opta": "Supplied by the CSU/DSU", "optb": "By the far end router", "optc": "By the clock rate command", "optd": "By the Physical layer bit stream timing", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Clocking on a serial interface is always provided by the CSU/DSU (DCE device). However, if you do not have a CSU/DSU in your nonproduction test environment, then you need to supply clocking with the clock rate command on the serial interface of the router with the DCE cable attached."}, {"question": "Which command is required for connectivity in a Frame Relay network if Inverse ARP is not operational?", "opta": "frame-relay arp", "optb": "frame-relay map", "optc": "frame-relay interface-dci", "optd": "frame-relay lmi-type", "ans": "B", "explanation": "If you have a router in your Frame Relay network that does not support IARP, you must create Frame Relay maps on your router, which provide known DLCI-to-IP address mappings."}, {"question": "How should a router that is being used in a Frame Relay network be configured to keep split horizon issues from preventing routing updates?", "opta": "Configure a separate subinterface for each PVC with a unique DLCI and subnet assigned to the subinterface.", "optb": "Configure each Frame Relay circuit as a point-to-point line to support multicast and broadcast traffic.", "optc": "Configure many subinterfaces in the same subnet.", "optd": "Configure a single subinterface to establish multiple PVC connections to multiple remote router interfaces.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "If you have a serial port configured with multiple DLCIs connected to multiple remote sites, split horizon rules, stop route updates received on an interface from being sent out the same interface. By creating subinterfaces for each PVC, you can avoid the split horizon issues when using Frame Relay."}, {"question": "Which of the following encapsulates PPP frames in Ethernet frames and uses common PPP features like authentication, encryption, and compression?", "opta": "PPP", "optb": "PPPoA", "optc": "PPPoE", "optd": "Token Ring", "ans": "C", "explanation": "PPPoE encapsulates PPP frames in Ethernet frames and uses common PPP features like authentication, encryption, and compression. PPPoA is used for ATM."}, {"question": "What is the frequency range of the IEEE 802.11a standard?", "opta": "2.4Gbps", "optb": "5Gbps", "optc": "2.4GHz", "optd": "5GHz", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11a standard runs in the 5GHz RF range."}, {"question": "What is the maximum distance running the lowest data rate for 802.11b?", "opta": "About 100 feet", "optb": "About 175 feet", "optc": "About 300 feet", "optd": "About 350 feet", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11b standard provides the lowest data rate at 1Mbps, but it also has the longest distance, which is about 350 feet."}, {"question": "What is the maximum distance with maximum data rate for 802.11a?", "opta": "About 65-75 feet", "optb": "About 90-100 feet", "optc": "About 150 feet", "optd": "Over 200 feet", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11a standard provides a maximum data rate of up to 54Mbps, but you need to be close to the access point, somewhere around 65 to 75 feet."}, {"question": "What is the frequency range of the IEEE 802.11b standard?", "opta": "2.4Gbps", "optb": "5Gbps", "optc": "2.4GHz", "optd": "5GHz", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11b and IEEE 802.11g standards both run in the 2.4GHz RF range."}, {"question": "You have a Cisco mesh network. What protocol allows multiple APs to connect with many redundant connections between nodes?", "opta": "LWAPP", "optb": "AWPP", "optc": "STP", "optd": "IEEE", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Each AP in a mesh network runs the Adaptive Wireless Path Protocol (AWPP). This protocol allows RAPs to communicate with each other to determine the best path back to the wired network via the RAP."}, {"question": "What is the maximum data rate for the 802.11g standard?", "opta": "6Mbps", "optb": "11Mbps", "optc": "22Mbps", "optd": "54Mbps", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11g standard provides a maximum data rate of up to 54Mbps."}, {"question": "What is the maximum data rate for the 802.11a standard?", "opta": "6Mbps", "optb": "11Mbps", "optc": "22Mbps", "optd": "54Mbps", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11a standard provides a maximum data rate of up to 54Mbps."}, {"question": "How many non-overlapping channels are available with 802.11b?", "opta": "3", "optb": "12", "optc": "23", "optd": "40", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11b standard provides 3 non-overlapping channels."}, {"question": "How many non-overlapping channels are available with 802.11a?", "opta": "3", "optb": "12", "optc": "23", "optd": "40", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11a standard provides up to 12 non-overlapping channels."}, {"question": "In Cisco's Unified Wireless Solution, what is the split-MAC architecture?", "opta": "The split-MAC architecture uses MAC addresses to create a forward/filter table and break up collision domains.", "optb": "The split-MAC architecture allows the splitting of 802.11 protocol packets between the AP and the controller to allow processing by both devices.", "optc": "The split-MAC architecture uses MAC addresses on the wireless network and IP addresses on the wired network.", "optd": "The split-MAC architecture uses MAC addresses to create a forward/filter table and break up broadcast domains.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The split-MAC architecture allows the splitting of 802.11 protocol packets between the Cisco LWAPP-based AP, which handles real-time portions of the protocol, and the WLAN controller, which handles those items that are not time sensitive."}, {"question": "What is the maximum distance with maximum data rate for 802.11b?", "opta": "About 65-75 feet", "optb": "About 90-100 feet", "optc": "About 150 feet", "optd": "Over 200 feet", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11b standard provides a maximum data rate of up to only 11Mbps, and you can be around 150 feet, maybe farther, depending on conditions."}, {"question": "What is the maximum distance with maximum data rate for 802.11g?", "opta": "About 65-75 feet", "optb": "About 90-100 feet", "optc": "About 150 feet", "optd": "Over 200 feet", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11g standard provides a maximum data rate of up to 54Mbps, but you need to be close to the access point, somewhere around 90 to 100 feet."}, {"question": "What is the maximum distance running the lowest data rate for 802.11a?", "opta": "About 100 feet", "optb": "About 175 feet", "optc": "About 300 feet", "optd": "About 350 feet", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11a standard's lowest data rate is 6Mbps, but it can run from a distance of about 175 feet."}, {"question": "How many non-overlapping channels are available with 802.11h?", "opta": "3", "optb": "12", "optc": "23", "optd": "40", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11h standard provides an addition 11 channels to the 802.11a standard's 12 non-overlapping channel for a total of 23 non-overlapping channels."}, {"question": "What is the maximum data rate for the 802.11b standard?", "opta": "6Mbps", "optb": "11Mbps", "optc": "22Mbps", "optd": "54Mbps", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11b standard provides a maximum data rate of up to 11Mbps."}, {"question": "You are connecting your access point and it is set to root. What does Extended Service Set ID mean?", "opta": "That you have more than one access point and they are in the same SSID connected by a distribution system.", "optb": "That you have more than one access point and they are in separate SSIDs connected by a distribution system.", "optc": "That you have multiple access points, but they are placed physically in different buildings.", "optd": "That you have multiple access points, but one is a repeater access point.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Extended Service Set ID means that you have more than one access point and they all are set to the same SSID and all are connected together in the same VLAN or distribution system so users can roam."}, {"question": "Cisco's Unified Wireless Solution provides a mesh solution. What devices do you absolutely need to purchase to run a Cisco solution?\n  WCS\n  Controller\n  Access point\n  Bridge", "opta": "1 and 2", "optb": "2 and 3", "optc": "1 and 4 only", "optd": "4 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "The Cisco Unified Wireless Solution is a great product, but you must purchase specialized devices. Cisco managed access points and a controller are the devices you need to purchase to run the Unified Wireless Solution."}, {"question": "What is the frequency range of the IEEE 802.11g standard?", "opta": "2.4Gbps", "optb": "5Gbps", "optc": "2.4GHz", "optd": "5GHz", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11b and IEEE 802.11g standards both run in the 2.4GHz RF range."}, {"question": "How many non-overlapping channels are available with 802.11g?", "opta": "3", "optb": "12", "optc": "23", "optd": "40", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11g standard provides 3 non-overlapping channels."}, {"question": "What is the maximum distance running the lowest data rate for 802.11g?", "opta": "About 100 feet", "optb": "About 175 feet", "optc": "About 300 feet", "optd": "About 350 feet", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The IEEE 802.11g standard's lowest data rate is 6Mbps, but it can run from a distance of about 300 feet."}]]}